<!--
SDWan Rules Range :- 113100-113500
BaseRules :- 113100,113200,113201
-->
<group name="versa-sdwan,">
	<!-- <rule id="113100" level="0" noalert="1">
		<decoded_as>versa-sd-wan</decoded_as>
		<description>Versa SDWAN Event</description>
        <group>info,one-on-one,</group>
	</rule> -->
	<rule id="113200" level="0" noalert="1">
		<decoded_as>json</decoded_as>
		<field name="productName" type="pcre2">SDWAN</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN Event</description>
        <group>info,one-on-one,</group>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113201" level="1" noalert="1">
		<!-- <if_sid>113100,113200</if_sid> -->
		<if_sid>113200</if_sid>
		<description>Versa SDWAN Event</description>
        <group>info,one-on-one,</group>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113101" level="1" noalert="1">
		<if_sid>113201</if_sid>
		<field name="log_type" type="pcre2">(?i)^alarmLog$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Alarm Logs</description>
        <group>info,one-on-one,</group>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113102" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^OSPF NeighbornState Change$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Detects a change in OSPF neighbor state (when applicable) Normally representative of a “flapping” condition.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule detects changes in the OSPF neighbor state, which can indicate a "flapping" condition. Such flapping often signals underlying network issues like congestion, hardware faults, or configuration problems, affecting network stability and routing reliability.
        </info>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1046,T1046.001,discovery,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1046</id>
			<id>T1046.001</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113103" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^cpu-utilization$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Generated when datapath CPU utilization exceeds configured threshold value.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: The rule triggers when datapath CPU utilization surpasses the set threshold. It also detects changes in OSPF neighbor state, indicating potential flapping conditions.
        </info>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1499,impact,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1499 </id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113104" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^mem-utilization$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Generated when datapath memory utilization exceeds configured threshold value.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when datapath memory utilization surpasses the set threshold, indicating potential performance issues or abnormal resource consumption. It helps in early detection of problems that may affect system stability and performance.
        </info>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1499,T1499.003,T1498,impact</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1499</id>
			<id>T1499.003</id>
			<id>T1498</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113105" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^disk-utilization$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Generated when disk utilization exceeds configured threshold value.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when disk utilization surpasses a predefined threshold, indicating potential issues such as insufficient disk space or excessive resource consumption. This can help prevent system slowdowns or outages by alerting you before reaching critical capacity levels.
        </info>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1070,T1070.004,T1565,defense-evasion,impact,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1070</id>
			<id>T1070.004</id>
			<id>T1565</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113106" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^org-session-utilization$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Generated when number of sessions of an org exceed configured number of sessions.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when the number of sessions for an organization surpasses a predefined threshold. It helps identify potential anomalies or unauthorized activity by flagging unusually high session counts, which could indicate excessive use, misuse, or security concerns.
        </info>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1078,T1098,T1071,T1499,defense-evasion,privilege-escalation,initial-access,command-control</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1078</id>
			<id>T1098</id>
			<id>T1071</id>
			<id>T1499</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113107" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^device-session-utilization$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Generated when number of sessions exceeds configured number of sessions for a device/appliance.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when the number of sessions exceeds the configured threshold for a device or appliance, indicating potential overload or abnormal activity. This may signal performance issues or a possible security threat requiring immediate attention.
        </info>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1110,T1499,credential-access,impact,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1110</id>
			<id>T1499</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113108" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^Interface-down$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Generated when an interface (or sub-interface) goes down.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when an interface or sub-interface goes down, as this event indicates a potential network disruption or connectivity issue that could impact overall network performance and reliability. It’s essential to monitor such events to ensure timely resolution and maintain network stability.
        </info>
		<group>high,one-on-one,T1498,impact,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1498</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113109" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^uplink-bw-threshold$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Generated when current uplink bandwidth exceeds configured uplink bandwidth of an interface.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when the current uplink bandwidth surpasses the configured bandwidth limit of an interface. This condition indicates potential network congestion or misconfiguration, which could affect network performance and reliability.
        </info>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1498,impact,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1498</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113110" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^dnlink-bw-threshold$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Generated when current downlink bandwidth exceeds configured uplink bandwidth of an interface.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when the downlink bandwidth of an interface exceeds the configured uplink bandwidth, indicating a potential bandwidth overload or misconfiguration. It helps identify unusual traffic patterns that could impact network performance or indicate possible issues with bandwidth allocation.
        </info>
		<group>low,one-on-one,T1498,impact,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1498</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113111" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^adc-server-down$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Generated when backend server does not respond to ADC monitor(s) for a specified amount of time.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when a backend server fails to respond to ADC monitors within the defined timeout period, indicating a potential issue with server availability or connectivity. It helps identify and address server downtime or performance problems promptly.
        </info>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1565,T1565.001,impact,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1565</id>
			<id>T1565.001</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113112" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^adc-vservice-down$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Generated when all backend server(s) attached to virtual service are declared down because of monitor health failure.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when all backend servers associated with a virtual service are reported as down due to health monitor failures. It indicates a critical issue where the virtual service is unable to route traffic to any healthy backend servers, potentially leading to service disruption.
        </info>
		<group>high,one-on-one,T1499,impact,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1499 </id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113113" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^cgnat-pool-utilization$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Generated when CGNAT pool exceeds configured threshold value or when pool is exhausted.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers an alert when the Carrier-Grade NAT (CGNAT) pool exceeds its configured threshold or becomes exhausted. It ensures prompt detection of potential IP address shortages, which could impact network connectivity and performance.
        </info>
		<group>high,one-on-one,T1071,T1071.001,command-control,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
			<id>T1071.001</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113114" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^snat-pool-utilization$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Generated when SNAT pool exceeds configured threshold value or when pool is exhausted.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers an alert when the Source Network Address Translation (SNAT) pool exceeds its configured threshold or becomes exhausted, indicating a potential overload or exhaustion of available IP addresses for translation. This helps in identifying and mitigating potential network issues or misconfigurations affecting network traffic.
        </info>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1071,T1071.001,T1046,command-control,discovery,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
			<id>T1071.001</id>
			<id>T1046</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113115" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^ipsec-tunneldown$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Generated when IPSEC tunnel with a peer goes down.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when an IPSEC tunnel with a peer goes down, indicating a potential issue with secure communications between endpoints. It helps in identifying disruptions in encrypted traffic, which may impact data security and connectivity.
        </info>
		<group>high,one-on-one,T1071,T1071.001,command-control,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
			<id>T1071.001</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113116" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^ipsec-ike-down$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Generated when IKE connection established with a peer goes down.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when an IKE connection with a peer is established but then goes down, indicating a potential issue with the VPN tunnel's availability or stability. Such events could signal misconfigurations, network disruptions, or security incidents that require immediate attention.
        </info>
		<group>high,one-on-one,T1076,T1036,lateral-movement,defense-evasion,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1076</id>
			<id>T1036</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113117" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^Interface Down$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Detects when an interface is down.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when an interface goes down, indicating potential network issues such as outages or configuration problems. Monitoring interface status is crucial for maintaining network reliability and identifying disruptions that could impact connectivity and performance.
        </info>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1489,impact,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1489</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113118" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^Branch Disconnect$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Detects when branch device is not connected to either controller.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when a branch device fails to connect to either of the two controllers, indicating potential network issues or configuration problems. It helps identify connectivity disruptions that could impact network performance and reliability.
        </info>
		<group>low,one-on-one,T1071,T1070,T1070.004,T1498,command-control,defense-evasion,impact,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
			<id>T1070</id>
			<id>T1070.004</id>
			<id>T1498</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113119" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^BGP Neighbor Down$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Detects when a BGP neighbor is not in an established state.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when a BGP neighbor is not in an established state, indicating a potential disruption in routing protocol communications. This can signal issues such as network connectivity problems, misconfigurations, or a possible security threat affecting BGP sessions.
        </info>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1565,T1071,T1078,impact,command-control,defense-evasion,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1565</id>
			<id>T1071</id>
			<id>T1078</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113120" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^Circuit Down$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Detects when a SDWAN overlay tunnel to both SD-WAN controllers is downacross any transport path.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when an SD-WAN overlay tunnel fails to connect to both SD-WAN controllers across any transport path, indicating a potential disruption in network communication.                        It helps identify critical connectivity issues that could affect the overall performance and reliability of the SD-WAN infrastructure.
        </info>
		<group>high,one-on-one,T1499,T1499.001,impact,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1499</id>
			<id>T1499.001</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113121" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^CPE Interface Bouncing$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Detects when interface on CTL provided CPE is bouncing.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when an interface on the Customer Premises Equipment (CPE) provided by the Centralized Transport Layer (CTL) is bouncing, indicating frequent up and down status changes. This behavior may signal potential network issues or instability, warranting further investigation to ensure network reliability and performance.
        </info>
		<group>low,one-on-one,T1562,T1562.001,defense-evasion,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1562</id>
			<id>T1562.001</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113122" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^CPE VRRP Switchover$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Failover between two appliances configured.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when a failover event is detected between two appliances, indicating a switch from the primary to the secondary appliance due to a fault or maintenance.
        </info>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,impact,T1499,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1499</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113123" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^bgp-nbr-state-change$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Generated when BGP between peers goes down or comes back up.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when there is a change in the BGP session status between peers, indicating a possible network connectivity issue or recovery.
        </info>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,impact,T1498,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1498</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113124" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^ddos-threshold$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Generated when DDOS traffic exceeds configured aggregate/classified DDOS threshold.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when the volume of DDOS traffic surpasses the configured threshold, indicating a potential distributed denial-of-service attack.
        </info>
		<group>high,one-on-one,impact,T1498,T1498.001,T1498.002,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1498</id>
			<id>T1498.001</id>
			<id>T1498.002</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113125" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^zone-protection-flood$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Generated when flood traffic exceeds configured zone protection threshold value.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when flood traffic surpasses the configured zone protection threshold, indicating a potential denial-of-service attack or excessive traffic load.
        </info>
		<group>high,one-on-one,impact,T1499,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1499</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113126" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^port-scan-flood$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Generated when PORT-SCAN from a source to destination exceeds configured zone protection profile value.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when a source IP exceeds the predefined threshold of port scans to a destination, indicating potential reconnaissance or scanning activity.
        </info>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,discovery,T1046,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1046</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113127" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^sdwan-branch-disconnect$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Generated a branch gets disconnected from Controller.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule will trigger when a branch loses connectivity to the SD-WAN controller, indicating a potential network issue or disruption.
        </info>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1071,command-control,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113128" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^sdwan-datapath-down$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Generated when all paths between two branches goes down.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when all communication paths between two branches in the SD-WAN network are down, indicating a complete loss of connectivity.
        </info>
		<group>high,one-on-one,command-control,exfiltration,T1071,T1030,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
			<id>T1030</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113129" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^sdwan-datapath-sla-not-met$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Generated when the path between two branches for a particular traffic class does not meet SLA.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule will trigger when the performance of the traffic path between two branches fails to meet the defined Service Level Agreement (SLA) requirements.
        </info>
		<group>high,one-on-one,discovery,T1046,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1046</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113130" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^dhcp-pool-utilization$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Generated when DHCP addresses are exhausted and no more addresses can be allocated from DHCP address pools.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when DHCP addresses are exhausted and no additional IP addresses are available for allocation from the configured address pools.
        </info>
		<group>low,one-on-one,impact,discovery,T1489,T1046,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1489</id>
			<id>T1046</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113131" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^appliance-not-subjugated$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Appliance not subjugated to Versa director.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule will trigger when an appliance is not under the control of Versa Director, indicating potential misconfiguration or unauthorized changes in network management.
        </info>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,execution,command-control,defense-evasion,credential-access,discovery,T1203,T1071,T1071.001,T1027,T1040,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1203</id>
			<id>T1071</id>
			<id>T1071.001</id>
			<id>T1027</id>
			<id>T1040</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
	<rule id="113132" level="1">
		<if_sid>113101</if_sid>
		<field name="AlarmType" type="pcre2">(?i)^app-stopped$</field>
		<description>Versa SDWAN: Appliance not subjugated to Versa director.</description>
		<info type="text">
          Description: This rule triggers when an appliance is not managed or monitored by Versa Director, indicating a potential configuration or deployment issue.
        </info>
		<group>high,one-on-one,initial-access,T1190,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1190</id>
		</mitre>
	</rule>
</group>