<!-- {"full_log":"Sep 23 11:28:21 10-1-19-106.prometheus-kube-prometheus-kube-proxy.kube-system.svc.cluster.local 0|Trend Micro|Deep-Discovery-Inspector:|6.7.1077|2184|Possible Successful Logon Connection - RDP (Request)|2|dvc=172.30.20.84 dvcmac=08:92:04:B0:DB:AC dvchost=PMUTMDDI01 deviceExternalId=A33106350B1B-47A88F98-AB88-7DD7-DD4D rt=Sep 23 2024 11:28:35 GMT+05:30 app=RDP deviceDirection=1 dhost=vwjump001.sidbifarm.com dst=172.30.3.228 dpt=3389 dmac=e8:f7:24:45:a0:7a shost=vwpimpri101.sidbifarm.com src=172.40.20.27 spt=62159 smac=02:30:f5:3a:02:00 fileType=-65536 fsize=0 act=not blocked cn3Label=Threat Type cn3=2 destinationTranslatedAddress=172.30.3.228 sourceTranslatedAddress=172.40.20.27 suid=eitadm_ta cnt=1 cat=Authentication cs6Label=pAttackPhase cs6=Lateral Movement flexNumber1Label=vLANId flexNumber1=4095 devicePayloadId=2:6200189: tenant=SIDBI logType=other cust1=logger01","L0":"ddd4b256-d7fe-47b5-bf3c-2c8669f35355","L1":"rrrrrrrr-rrrr-rrrr-rrrr-rrrrrrrrrrrr","L2":"a8eee020-d655-40f8-98b8-bdc5a6a9e45c","L3":"fbdbbd91-9eba-479e-902c-6f857cc81365"} -->
<group name="deep-discovery-inspector,">
	<rule id="116800" level="0" noalert="1">
		<decoded_as>json</decoded_as>
		<field name="product_name" type="pcre2">(?i)^Deep\sDiscovery\sInspector$</field>
		<description>Deep-Discovery-Inspector: Log event detected.</description>
	</rule>
	<!-- <rule id="116801" level="0" noalert="1">
		<decoded_as>dd-inspector</decoded_as>
		<description>Deep-Discovery-Inspector: Log event detected.</description>
	</rule> -->
	<rule id="116802" level="1" noalert="1">
		<!-- <if_sid>116800,116801</if_sid> -->
		<if_sid>116800</if_sid>
		<description>Deep-Discovery-Inspector: Log event detected.</description>
	</rule>
	<!-- * -->
	<rule id="116803" level="1" noalert="1">
		<if_sid>116802</if_sid>
		<field name="threat_type" type="pcre2">^2$</field>
		<description>Deep-Discovery-Inspector: Suspicious behavior log detected.</description>
		<group>low,one-on-one,info,T1078,privilege-escalation,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1078</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : Detecting a suspicious behavior log from DD-Inspector indicates that an application or user activity may be exhibiting unusual patterns that could signify a security threat. DD-Inspector monitors application behavior and captures logs that highlight anomalies, such as unexpected changes in user permissions, unusual access to sensitive data, or repeated failed login attempts. When such logs are flagged, it's important to investigate the underlying cause to determine if there is a potential security breach or misuse of the application.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116804" level="1" noalert="1">
		<if_sid>116802</if_sid>
		<field name="threat_type" type="pcre2">^3$</field>
		<description>Deep-Discovery-Inspector: Exploit log detected.</description>
		<group>low,one-on-one,info,T1190,initial-access,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1190</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : Detecting an exploit log from DD-Inspector suggests that a potential vulnerability has been targeted within an application or system. DD-Inspector, designed for monitoring application behavior, captures logs that indicate suspicious activities, such as unauthorized access attempts, code injection, or abnormal system calls. When such logs are identified, it’s crucial to investigate further to determine if an actual exploit has occurred and assess the extent of any potential damage.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116805" level="1" noalert="1">
		<if_sid>116802</if_sid>
		<field name="threat_type" type="pcre2">^6$</field>
		<description>Deep-Discovery-Inspector: Disruptive application log detected.</description>
		<group>low,one-on-one,T1078,privilege-escalation,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1078</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : Detecting a disruptive application log from DD-Inspector indicates that the application is generating unusual or harmful activity that could impact system performance or security. DD-Inspector, a tool for monitoring and analyzing application behavior, can identify logs that signify issues such as excessive resource usage, error messages, or unauthorized access attempts. When such logs are detected, it’s essential to investigate the underlying causes to determine if the application is malfunctioning or being exploited.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116806" level="1" noalert="1">
		<if_sid>116802</if_sid>
		<field name="threat_type" type="pcre2">^0$</field>
		<description>Deep-Discovery-Inspector: Malicious content log detected.</description>
		<group>low,one-on-one,T1203,execution,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1203</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : The detection of a malicious content log by DD-Inspector signifies a potential security breach within the network. This log captures critical information regarding harmful files, links, or activities that could jeopardize system integrity and data security. Key details such as timestamps, source IP addresses, and threat types are recorded, allowing security teams to assess the severity and origin of the threat. Immediate investigation and response are essential to contain the risk, including isolating affected systems and analyzing attack vectors.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116807" level="1" noalert="1">
		<if_sid>116802</if_sid>
		<field name="threat_type" type="pcre2">^1$</field>
		<description>Deep-Discovery-Inspector: Malicious behaviour log detected.</description>
		<group>low,one-on-one,T1071,command-and-control,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : The detection of a malicious behavior log by DD-Inspector indicates the identification of suspicious or harmful activities within the network. This log provides critical insights into behaviors that may signal a potential security threat, such as unauthorized access attempts, unusual file modifications, or anomalous user activity. Detailed entries, including timestamps and source identifiers, help security teams trace the origin and nature of the threat. Prompt investigation is essential to mitigate risks, which may involve isolating affected systems and implementing countermeasures.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116808" level="1" noalert="1">
		<if_sid>116802</if_sid>
		<field name="threat_type" type="pcre2">^4$</field>
		<description>Deep-Discovery-Inspector: Grayware log detected.</description>
		<group>low,one-on-one,T1070,defense-evasion,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1070</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : The detection of a grayware log by DD-Inspector highlights the presence of potentially unwanted programs that, while not strictly malicious, can negatively impact system performance and security. Grayware can include adware, spyware, and other software that may compromise user privacy or introduce vulnerabilities. The log captures essential information such as the type of grayware detected, its source, and the behaviors exhibited, allowing security teams to assess the level of risk associated with these programs.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116809" level="1">
		<if_sid>116802</if_sid>
		<field name="file_status" type="pcre2">^\-1$</field>
		<field name="risk_level" type="pcre2">^3$</field>
		<description>Deep-Discovery-Inspector: Malicious $(file_type) unknown file with high risk detected in Sandbox.</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1204,T1204.002,T1497,execution,discovery,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1204</id>
			<id>T1204.002</id>
			<id>T1497</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : A high-risk malicious file type has been detected in the sandbox environment. This unknown file type has raised red flags due to its potentially harmful behavior, which could pose a threat to the system. The sandbox allows for safe examination of the file, isolating it from the main network to prevent any damage. Immediate action is needed, including quarantining the file and investigating its origin and behavior to understand the risks involved.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116810" level="1">
		<if_sid>116802</if_sid>
		<field name="file_status" type="pcre2">^\-1$</field>
		<field name="risk_level" type="pcre2">^2$</field>
		<description>Deep-Discovery-Inspector: Malicious $(file_type) unknown file with medium risk detected in Sandbox.</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1204,T1204.002,T1497,execution,discovery,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1204</id>
			<id>T1204.002</id>
			<id>T1497</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : A medium-risk malicious file type has been detected in the sandbox environment. This means an unknown file type has been identified as potentially harmful to the system. The sandbox allows for safe examination of this file without affecting the main network. Security teams need to investigate further to determine the file’s source and potential impact. It’s important to monitor or quarantine the file to reduce any risk.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116811" level="1">
		<if_sid>116802</if_sid>
		<field name="file_status" type="pcre2">^0$</field>
		<field name="risk_level" type="pcre2">^3$</field>
		<description>Deep-Discovery-Inspector: Malicious $(file_type) bad file with high risk detected in Sandbox.</description>
		<group>high,one-on-one,s-a,T1204,T1204.002,T1497,execution,discovery,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1204</id>
			<id>T1204.002</id>
			<id>T1497</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : A high-risk malicious file type has been detected in the sandbox environment. This bad file has shown harmful behavior that could pose a serious threat to system security. By analyzing the file in the sandbox, security teams can observe its actions—such as attempting to access sensitive data or communicate with external servers—without risking the main network. The high-risk classification means immediate attention is needed to investigate the file’s origin and potential impact. If malicious behavior is confirmed, the file can be quarantined or deleted to prevent any harm.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116812" level="1">
		<if_sid>116802</if_sid>
		<field name="file_status" type="pcre2">^0$</field>
		<field name="risk_level" type="pcre2">^2$</field>
		<description>Deep-Discovery-Inspector: Malicious $(file_type) bad file with medium risk detected in Sandbox.</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1204,T1204.002,T1497,execution,discovery,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1204</id>
			<id>T1204.002</id>
			<id>T1497</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : A medium-risk malicious file type has been detected in the sandbox environment. This bad file has exhibited potentially harmful behavior that could affect system security. By running the file in the sandbox, security teams can safely observe its actions—such as attempts to access sensitive information or communicate with external servers—without risking the main network. While the risk level is categorized as medium, it’s important to investigate the file further to determine its origin and potential effects.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116813" level="1">
		<if_sid>116803</if_sid>
		<field name="severity" type="pcre2">^4$</field>
		<description>Deep Discovery Inspector: Low severity alert for $(event_name) detected</description>
		<group>low,one-on-one,T1598,T1087,T1078,discovery,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1598</id>
			<id>T1087</id>
			<id>T1078</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : The Deep Discovery Inspector has issued a low severity alert regarding this event name. This indicates the detection of an event that may not pose an immediate threat but still warrants attention. While the risk is considered low, it's important for security teams to review the details of the alert to understand the context and potential implications. Monitoring such alerts helps in identifying patterns that could indicate emerging issues over time.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116814" level="1">
		<if_sid>116803</if_sid>
		<field name="severity" type="pcre2">^6$</field>
		<description>Deep Discovery Inspector: Medium severity alert for $(event_name) detected</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1598,T1087,T1078,discovery,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1598</id>
			<id>T1087</id>
			<id>T1078</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : The Deep Discovery Inspector has generated a medium severity alert concerning this event name, indicating the detection of potentially harmful activity that requires timely attention. This alert suggests that while the threat may not be immediate, it could escalate if not addressed. Security teams should thoroughly investigate the details of the alert, including affected systems, timestamps, and associated user actions, to assess the nature and potential impact of the event. Monitoring medium severity alerts is essential for identifying patterns that could point to more serious vulnerabilities.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116815" level="1">
		<if_sid>116803</if_sid>
		<field name="severity" type="pcre2">^8$</field>
		<description>Deep Discovery Inspector: High severity alert for $(event_name) detected</description>
		<group>high,one-on-one,s-a,T1598,T1087,T1078,discovery,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1598</id>
			<id>T1087</id>
			<id>T1078</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : The Deep Discovery Inspector has issued a high severity alert related to this event name, indicating a significant threat that requires immediate action. This alert suggests the detection of potentially damaging activity, such as unauthorized access attempts, malware infections, or data exfiltration, which could compromise system integrity and sensitive information. Security teams must prioritize the investigation of this alert, examining key details such as affected systems, timestamps, and user actions to understand the scope and nature of the threat. Rapid response is critical; containment measures should be implemented immediately to mitigate risks and prevent further impact.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116816" level="1">
		<if_sid>116804</if_sid>
		<field name="severity" type="pcre2">^4$</field>
		<description>Deep Discovery Inspector: Low severity alert for $(event_name) detected</description>
		<group>low,one-on-one,T1203,T1068,T1190,privilege-escalation,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1203</id>
			<id>T1068</id>
			<id>T1190</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : The Deep Discovery Inspector has issued a low severity alert regarding this event name. This indicates the detection of an event that may not pose an immediate threat but still warrants attention. While the risk is considered low, it's important for security teams to review the details of the alert to understand the context and potential implications. Monitoring such alerts helps in identifying patterns that could indicate emerging issues over time.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116817" level="1">
		<if_sid>116804</if_sid>
		<field name="severity" type="pcre2">^6$</field>
		<description>Deep Discovery Inspector: Medium severity alert for $(event_name) detected</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1203,T1068,T1190,privilege-escalation,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1203 </id>
			<id>T1068</id>
			<id>T1190</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : The Deep Discovery Inspector has generated a medium severity alert concerning this event name, indicating the detection of potentially harmful activity that requires timely attention. This alert suggests that while the threat may not be immediate, it could escalate if not addressed. Security teams should thoroughly investigate the details of the alert, including affected systems, timestamps, and associated user actions, to assess the nature and potential impact of the event. Monitoring medium severity alerts is essential for identifying patterns that could point to more serious vulnerabilities.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116818" level="1">
		<if_sid>116804</if_sid>
		<field name="severity" type="pcre2">^8$</field>
		<description>Deep Discovery Inspector: High severity alert for $(event_name) detected</description>
		<group>high,one-on-one,s-a,T1203,T1068,T1190,privilege-escalation,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1190</id>
			<id>T1203</id>
			<id>T1068</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : The Deep Discovery Inspector has issued a high severity alert related to this event name, indicating a significant threat that requires immediate action. This alert suggests the detection of potentially damaging activity, such as unauthorized access attempts, malware infections, or data exfiltration, which could compromise system integrity and sensitive information. Security teams must prioritize the investigation of this alert, examining key details such as affected systems, timestamps, and user actions to understand the scope and nature of the threat. Rapid response is critical; containment measures should be implemented immediately to mitigate risks and prevent further impact.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116819" level="1">
		<if_sid>116805</if_sid>
		<field name="severity" type="pcre2">^4$</field>
		<description>Deep Discovery Inspector: Low severity alert for $(event_name) detected</description>
		<group>low,one-on-one,T1071,T1059,T1485,command-and-control,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
			<id>T1059</id>
			<id>T1485</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : The Deep Discovery Inspector has issued a low severity alert regarding this event name. This indicates the detection of an event that may not pose an immediate threat but still warrants attention. While the risk is considered low, it's important for security teams to review the details of the alert to understand the context and potential implications. Monitoring such alerts helps in identifying patterns that could indicate emerging issues over time.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116820" level="1">
		<if_sid>116805</if_sid>
		<field name="severity" type="pcre2">^6$</field>
		<description>Deep Discovery Inspector: Medium severity alert for $(event_name) detected</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1071,T1059,T1485,command-and-control,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
			<id>T1059</id>
			<id>T1485</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : The Deep Discovery Inspector has generated a medium severity alert concerning this event name, indicating the detection of potentially harmful activity that requires timely attention. This alert suggests that while the threat may not be immediate, it could escalate if not addressed. Security teams should thoroughly investigate the details of the alert, including affected systems, timestamps, and associated user actions, to assess the nature and potential impact of the event. Monitoring medium severity alerts is essential for identifying patterns that could point to more serious vulnerabilities.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116821" level="1">
		<if_sid>116805</if_sid>
		<field name="severity" type="pcre2">^8$</field>
		<description>Deep Discovery Inspector: High severity alert for $(event_name) detected</description>
		<group>high,one-on-one,s-a,T1071,T1059,T1485,command-and-control,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
			<id>T1059</id>
			<id>T1485</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : The Deep Discovery Inspector has issued a high severity alert related to this event name, indicating a significant threat that requires immediate action. This alert suggests the detection of potentially damaging activity, such as unauthorized access attempts, malware infections, or data exfiltration, which could compromise system integrity and sensitive information. Security teams must prioritize the investigation of this alert, examining key details such as affected systems, timestamps, and user actions to understand the scope and nature of the threat. Rapid response is critical; containment measures should be implemented immediately to mitigate risks and prevent further impact.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116822" level="1">
		<if_sid>116806</if_sid>
		<field name="severity" type="pcre2">^4$</field>
		<description>Deep Discovery Inspector: Low severity alert for $(event_name) detected</description>
		<group>low,one-on-one,T1064,T1203,T1068,execution,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1064</id>
			<id>T1203</id>
			<id>T1068</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : The Deep Discovery Inspector has issued a low severity alert regarding this event name. This indicates the detection of an event that may not pose an immediate threat but still warrants attention. While the risk is considered low, it's important for security teams to review the details of the alert to understand the context and potential implications. Monitoring such alerts helps in identifying patterns that could indicate emerging issues over time.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116823" level="1">
		<if_sid>116806</if_sid>
		<field name="severity" type="pcre2">^6$</field>
		<description>Deep Discovery Inspector: Medium severity alert for $(event_name) detected</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1064,T1203,T1068,execution,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1064</id>
			<id>T1203</id>
			<id>T1068</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : The Deep Discovery Inspector has generated a medium severity alert concerning this event name, indicating the detection of potentially harmful activity that requires timely attention. This alert suggests that while the threat may not be immediate, it could escalate if not addressed. Security teams should thoroughly investigate the details of the alert, including affected systems, timestamps, and associated user actions, to assess the nature and potential impact of the event. Monitoring medium severity alerts is essential for identifying patterns that could point to more serious vulnerabilities.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116824" level="1">
		<if_sid>116806</if_sid>
		<field name="severity" type="pcre2">^8$</field>
		<description>Deep Discovery Inspector: High severity alert for $(event_name) detected</description>
		<group>high,one-on-one,s-a,T1064,T1203,T1068,execution,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1064</id>
			<id>T1203</id>
			<id>T1068</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : The Deep Discovery Inspector has issued a high severity alert related to this event name, indicating a significant threat that requires immediate action. This alert suggests the detection of potentially damaging activity, such as unauthorized access attempts, malware infections, or data exfiltration, which could compromise system integrity and sensitive information. Security teams must prioritize the investigation of this alert, examining key details such as affected systems, timestamps, and user actions to understand the scope and nature of the threat. Rapid response is critical; containment measures should be implemented immediately to mitigate risks and prevent further impact.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116825" level="1">
		<if_sid>116807</if_sid>
		<field name="severity" type="pcre2">^4$</field>
		<description>Deep Discovery Inspector: Low severity alert for $(event_name) detected</description>
		<group>low,one-on-one,T1071,T1059,T1068,defense-evasion,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
			<id>T1059</id>
			<id>T1068</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : The Deep Discovery Inspector has issued a low severity alert regarding this event name. This indicates the detection of an event that may not pose an immediate threat but still warrants attention. While the risk is considered low, it's important for security teams to review the details of the alert to understand the context and potential implications. Monitoring such alerts helps in identifying patterns that could indicate emerging issues over time.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116826" level="1">
		<if_sid>116807</if_sid>
		<field name="severity" type="pcre2">^6$</field>
		<description>Deep Discovery Inspector: Medium severity alert for $(event_name) detected</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1071,T1059,T1068,defense-evasion,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
			<id>T1059</id>
			<id>T1068</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : The Deep Discovery Inspector has generated a medium severity alert concerning this event name, indicating the detection of potentially harmful activity that requires timely attention. This alert suggests that while the threat may not be immediate, it could escalate if not addressed. Security teams should thoroughly investigate the details of the alert, including affected systems, timestamps, and associated user actions, to assess the nature and potential impact of the event. Monitoring medium severity alerts is essential for identifying patterns that could point to more serious vulnerabilities.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116827" level="1">
		<if_sid>116807</if_sid>
		<field name="severity" type="pcre2">^8$</field>
		<description>Deep Discovery Inspector: High severity alert for $(event_name) detected</description>
		<group>high,one-on-one,s-a,,T1071,T1059,T1068,defense-evasion,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
			<id>T1059</id>
			<id>T1068</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : The Deep Discovery Inspector has issued a high severity alert related to this event name, indicating a significant threat that requires immediate action. This alert suggests the detection of potentially damaging activity, such as unauthorized access attempts, malware infections, or data exfiltration, which could compromise system integrity and sensitive information. Security teams must prioritize the investigation of this alert, examining key details such as affected systems, timestamps, and user actions to understand the scope and nature of the threat. Rapid response is critical; containment measures should be implemented immediately to mitigate risks and prevent further impact.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116828" level="1">
		<if_sid>116808</if_sid>
		<field name="severity" type="pcre2">^4$</field>
		<description>Deep Discovery Inspector: Low severity alert for $(event_name) detected</description>
		<group>low,one-on-one,T1070,T1064,T1203,T1495,defense-evasion,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1070</id>
			<id>T1064</id>
			<id>T1203</id>
			<id>T1495</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : The Deep Discovery Inspector has issued a low severity alert regarding this event name. This indicates the detection of an event that may not pose an immediate threat but still warrants attention. While the risk is considered low, it's important for security teams to review the details of the alert to understand the context and potential implications. Monitoring such alerts helps in identifying patterns that could indicate emerging issues over time.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116829" level="1">
		<if_sid>116808</if_sid>
		<field name="severity" type="pcre2">^6$</field>
		<description>Deep Discovery Inspector: Medium severity alert for $(event_name) detected</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1070,T1064,T1203,T1495,defense-evasion,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1070</id>
			<id>T1064</id>
			<id>T1203</id>
			<id>T1495</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : The Deep Discovery Inspector has generated a medium severity alert concerning this event name, indicating the detection of potentially harmful activity that requires timely attention. This alert suggests that while the threat may not be immediate, it could escalate if not addressed. Security teams should thoroughly investigate the details of the alert, including affected systems, timestamps, and associated user actions, to assess the nature and potential impact of the event. Monitoring medium severity alerts is essential for identifying patterns that could point to more serious vulnerabilities.
        </info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="116830" level="1">
		<if_sid>116808</if_sid>
		<field name="severity" type="pcre2">^8$</field>
		<description>Deep Discovery Inspector: High severity alert for $(event_name) detected</description>
		<group>high,one-on-one,s-a,T1070,T1064,T1203,T1495,defense-evasion,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1070</id>
			<id>T1064</id>
			<id>T1203</id>
			<id>T1495</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">
        Description : The Deep Discovery Inspector has issued a high severity alert related to this event name, indicating a significant threat that requires immediate action. This alert suggests the detection of potentially damaging activity, such as unauthorized access attempts, malware infections, or data exfiltration, which could compromise system integrity and sensitive information. Security teams must prioritize the investigation of this alert, examining key details such as affected systems, timestamps, and user actions to understand the scope and nature of the threat. Rapid response is critical; containment measures should be implemented immediately to mitigate risks and prevent further impact.
        </info>
	</rule>
</group>