<!-- {"full_log":"0|Forcepoint|Security|8.5.0|76|Transaction permitted|1| act=permitted app=https dvc=192.168.101.26 dst=142.250.183.228 dhost=www.google.com dpt=443 src=192.168.101.141 spt=65412 suser=LDAP:\/\/ABADC OU\\=H-CP,OU\\=Harohalli,DC\\=anthembio,DC\\=com\/Deepak Shanmugasundaram loginID=deepak.s1 destinationTranslatedPort=28047 rt=1729854543 in=1224 out=979 requestMethod=GET requestClientApplication=Mozilla\/5.0 (Windows NT 10.0; Win64; x64; rv:130.0) Gecko\/20100101 Firefox\/130.0 reason=- cs1Label=Policy cs1=Super Administrator**Default cs2Label=DynCat cs2=0 cs3Label=ContentType cs3=application\/json; charset\\=UTF-8 cn1Label=DispositionCode cn1=1026 cn2Label=ScanDuration cn2=12 request=https:\/\/www.google.com\/complete\/search?q\\=surface%20finish%20requirements%20for%20i&cp\\=33&client\\=gws-wiz-serp&xssi\\=t&gs_pcrt\\=undefined&hl\\=en-IN&authuser\\=0&pq\\=surface%20finish%20requirements&psi\\=_nsbZ-7AFJyQnesP8JCY6QU.1729854463790&gs_mss\\=surface%20finish%20requirements%20&dpr\\=1 logRecordSource=OnPrem tenant=ABPLBS productName=Forcepointproxy ProductType=Proxy logType=network","tenant":"ABPLBS","productName":"Forcepointproxy","productType":"Proxy","logType":"network","L0":"050ab1ad-01d1-4fd5-aeff-17788fe0e6fb","L1":"rrrrrrrr-rrrr-rrrr-rrrr-rrrrrrrrrrrr","L2":"rrrrrrrr-rrrr-rrrr-rrrr-rrrrrrrrrrrr","L3":"b6544898-5642-4fea-bdf0-eac4fc4d0e17"} -->

<group name= "forcepoint-proxy,">
	<!-- Base Rule -->
	<!-- <rule id="104700" level="0" noalert="1">
		<decoded_as>forcepoint-proxy-json</decoded_as>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy Events</description>
		<group>info,one-on-one</group>
	</rule> -->
	<!-- <rule id="104701" level="0" noalert="1"> -->
		
	<rule id="104702" level="0" noalert="1">
		<decoded_as>json</decoded_as>
		<field name="product_name" type="pcre2">(?i)^security$</field>
		<field name="vendor" type="pcre2">(?i)^Forcepoint$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy Events</description>
		<group>info,one-on-one</group>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104727" level="1">
		<if_sid>104702</if_sid>
		<list field="src_ip">etc/lists/activelist-ips</list>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Potential inbound connection detected to known malicious IP address.</description>
		<group>high,one-on-one,s-a,inbound,T1071,command-and-control,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: A security alert was triggered due to the detection of an inbound connection attempt from a known malicious IP address. This may indicate an adversary trying to establish communication with the internal network, potentially to exploit vulnerabilities, deploy malware, or gain unauthorized access to sensitive data. Immediate investigation and blocking of the IP are recommended to prevent further risk, as this connection could be part of a broader attack campaign or reconnaissance activity aimed at identifying weaknesses within the system.
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104728" level="1">
		<if_sid>104702</if_sid>
		<list field="src_ip">etc/lists/activelist-threatintel-ip</list>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Potential inbound connection detected to known malicious IP address.</description>
		<group>high,one-on-one,s-a,inbound,T1071,command-and-control,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: A potential outbound connection was detected to a known malicious IP address, suggesting that an internal system may have been compromised. This could indicate that malware is attempting to exfiltrate data or communicate with a command-and-control (C2) server. Immediate investigation is required to identify the affected system and block the malicious traffic to prevent further damage or data loss.
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104729" level="1">
		<if_sid>104702</if_sid>
		<list field="dst_ip">etc/lists/activelist-ips</list>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Potential outbound connection detected to known malicious IP address.</description>
		<group>high,one-on-one,s-a,outbound,T1071,command-and-control,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: A potential outbound connection was detected to a known malicious IP address, suggesting that an internal system may have been compromised. This could indicate that malware is attempting to exfiltrate data or communicate with a command-and-control (C2) server. Immediate investigation is required to identify the affected system and block the malicious traffic to prevent further damage or data loss.
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104730" level="1">
		<if_sid>104702</if_sid>
		<list field="dst_ip">etc/lists/activelist-threatintel-ip</list>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Potential outbound connection detected to known malicious IP address.</description>
		<group>high,one-on-one,s-a,outbound,T1071,command-and-control,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description:  A security alert was triggered due to the detection of an inbound connection attempt from a known malicious IP address. This may indicate an adversary trying to establish communication with the internal network, potentially to exploit vulnerabilities, deploy malware, or gain unauthorized access to sensitive data. Immediate investigation and blocking of the IP are recommended to prevent further risk, as this connection could be part of a broader attack campaign or reconnaissance activity aimed at identifying weaknesses within the system.
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104731" level="1">
		<if_sid>104702</if_sid>
		<list field="request_url">etc/lists/activelist-proxy</list>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Detected potential access attempt to suspicious URL.</description>
		<group>high,one-on-one,s-a,T1071,command-and-control,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: A potential access attempt to a suspicious URL was identified, indicating that either an internal user or a compromised system may be trying to establish a connection with a malicious site. This activity could be associated with phishing, an attempt to download malware, or communication with a command-and-control (C2) server, which poses a significant risk to the network. Immediate action is required to block the URL and initiate an investigation into the source of the attempt. Failure to address this could lead to data exfiltration, malware infection, or further network compromise. Preventive measures should be taken to mitigate any potential harm.
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104732" level="1">
		<if_sid>104702</if_sid>
		<list field="request_url">etc/lists/activelist-threatintel-domain</list>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Detected potential access attempt to suspicious URL.</description>
		<group>high,one-on-one,s-a,T1071,command-and-control,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description:  A potential access attempt to a suspicious URL was identified, indicating that either an internal user or a compromised system may be trying to establish a connection with a malicious site. This activity could be associated with phishing, an attempt to download malware, or communication with a command-and-control (C2) server, which poses a significant risk to the network. Immediate action is required to block the URL and initiate an investigation into the source of the attempt. Failure to address this could lead to data exfiltration, malware infection, or further network compromise. Preventive measures should be taken to mitigate any potential harm.
	</info>
	</rule>
	<!-- Product base Rule -->
	<rule id="104703" level="0" noalert="1">
		<if_sid>104702</if_sid>
		<action type="pcre2">(?i)permitted</action>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Triggered action for permitted process.</description>
		<group>info,one-on-one</group>
	</rule>

	<rule id="104704" level="0" noalert="1">
		<if_sid>104702</if_sid>
		<action type="pcre2">(?i)blocked</action>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Triggered action for blocked process.</description>
		<group>info,one-on-one</group>
	</rule>

	<!-- Product Rule -->
	<rule id="104740" level="1">
		<if_sid>104703</if_sid>
		<field name="disposition_code" type="pcre2">^1028$</field>
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^128$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Malicious website access detected in permitted transaction.</description>
		<group>high,one-on-one,s-a,T1204.002,T1204,execution,notable-behaviour,allowed,malicious,url,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1204.002</id>
			<id>T1204</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">description : This rule detects and logs instances where a transaction to a known or suspected malicious website was permitted by the Forcepoint Proxy. A transaction refers to any interaction between the user's browser and the web server, including accessing web pages, downloading files, or exchanging data. Normally, transactions to malicious websites are blocked by security controls, but in this case, the transaction was allowed to proceed, which could indicate a security policy exception, a misconfiguration, or an override.
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104705" level="1">  
		<if_sid>104703</if_sid>
		<!-- <field name="disposition_code" type="pcre2">^1048$</field> -->
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^194$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Suspicious content detected in permitted file.</description>
		<group>high,one-on-one,s-a,T1204.002,T1204,execution,notable-behaviour,suspicious-content,allowed,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1204.002</id>
			<id>T1204</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">description : This rule triggers when a file flagged as containing suspicious content is permitted to be downloaded or accessed through the Forcepoint Proxy. Suspicious content generally refers to files that exhibit behaviors or characteristics associated with malicious activity, such as unusual file types, obfuscated code, or unexpected modifications. The rule highlights potential risks where files that could compromise the security of the network or users were allowed to pass through security controls.
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104706" level="1">
		<if_sid>104704</if_sid>
		<!-- <field name="disposition_code" type="pcre2">^1027$</field> -->
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^8$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Blocked transaction identified in special events category.</description>
		<group>low,one-on-one,T1562.006,T1562,defense-evasion,policy-violation,blocked,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1562.006</id>
			<id>T1562</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: This rule detects when a transaction is blocked by Forcepoint Proxy due to the content being categorized under "Special Events." The "Special Events" category could represent high-priority or restricted content, indicating that a user attempted to access such content, which was then blocked by the proxy.
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104707" level="1">   
		<if_sid>104703</if_sid>
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^73$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Detect authorized access to political organizations.</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1078,T1078.003,defense-evasion,notable-behaviour,allowed,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1078</id>
			<id>T1078.003</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: "Detecting Authorized Access to Political Organizations" involves identifying and confirming legitimate access to the systems and networks of political entities, ensuring that only authorized individuals or groups are granted entry. This process begins with monitoring and analyzing access logs, where any attempts to access sensitive information or systems are tracked. Security systems use authentication mechanisms like multi-factor authentication (MFA) to verify the identity of users attempting to access these networks. Any unauthorized or suspicious login attempts are flagged for investigation. If legitimate access is detected, security teams ensure that the proper permissions and protocols are being followed to protect sensitive political data. This may involve tracking who accessed what information and when, and ensuring compliance with data protection regulations. Authorized access is also monitored for unusual or excessive activity, which could signal potential internal or external threats. If any anomalies are detected, additional security measures, like restricting access or conducting a deeper investigation, are applied to ensure the integrity of the organization's systems.
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104708" level="1">
		<if_sid>104704</if_sid>
		<!-- <field name="disposition_code" type="pcre2">^1027$</field> -->
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^90$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Blocked threat from abused drugs category.</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1566,initial-access,threat,blocked,malicious,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1566</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: This rule triggers when a a web request was blocked by Forcepoint Proxy due to its categorization under "Abused Drugs." The "Abused Drugs" category typically encompasses websites and content related to the illegal sale, distribution, or promotion of controlled substances and drugs. The blocking action was taken to prevent access to potentially harmful or illicit content, ensuring compliance with organizational policies and protecting users from exposure to such material.
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104709" level="1">  
		<if_sid>104703</if_sid>
		<!-- <field name="disposition_code" type="pcre2">^1048$</field> -->
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^94$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Permitted file access from adult category detected.</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1222,defense-evasion,notable-behaviour,policy-violation,allowed,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1222</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: This rule triggers when a file was permitted by Forcepoint Proxy despite its categorization under "Adult." The "Adult" category generally includes websites and content related to explicit or adult material. The permission of this file suggests that it might have been flagged as part of an exception or allowed under specific conditions defined in the organization's access control policies. This action ensures that legitimate or required content, despite its classification, can still be accessed when necessary for business purposes.
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104710" level="1">  
		<if_sid>104703</if_sid>
		<!-- <field name="disposition_code" type="pcre2">^1027$</field> -->
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^80$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - potential authorized access to hacking activities detected.</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1567,exfiltration,notable-behaviour,permitted,malicious,url,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1567</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: a transaction was permitted by Forcepoint Proxy due to its categorization under "Hacking." The "Hacking" category typically includes websites, tools, or content associated with unauthorized access, exploitation of vulnerabilities, or other cybercriminal activities. The blocking action was taken to prevent interaction with potentially harmful or illegal content, thereby protecting the organization from security threats and ensuring compliance with cybersecurity policies.
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104711" level="1">  
		<if_sid>104703</if_sid>
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^128$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Permitted file access from malicious link.</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1204.002,T1204,execution,threat,malicious-behaviour,malicious,allowed,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1204</id>
			<id>T1204.002</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: a file was permitted by Forcepoint Proxy despite originating from a source categorized as "Malicious Link." The "Malicious Link" category typically includes URLs or domains associated with phishing, malware distribution, or other malicious activities. The permission of this file suggests that it was allowed based on specific organizational exceptions or overrides, possibly due to a validated source or a controlled environment where the threat has been assessed and managed. 
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104712" level="1">  
		<if_sid>104703</if_sid>
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^193$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Detect potential access to emerging exploits.</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1190,T1068,initial-access,privilege-escalation,authentication,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1190</id>
			<id>T1068</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: Detecting potential access to emerging exploits requires a proactive and multi-layered approach. This involves continuous monitoring of threat intelligence feeds, regular vulnerability scanning, and the implementation of robust intrusion detection systems. By analyzing network traffic patterns, identifying anomalous behavior, and correlating security events with known vulnerabilities, organizations can quickly detect and respond to emerging threats. Utilizing security information and event management (SIEM) systems and leveraging machine learning algorithms for threat detection can significantly enhance the ability to identify and respond to novel exploits before they cause significant damage.
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104713" level="1">  
		<if_sid>104703</if_sid>
		<!-- <field name="disposition_code" type="pcre2">^1044$</field> -->
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^166$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Permitted access via keyword match for detecting security keyloggers.</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1056,T1056.001,T1556,collection,credential-access,defense-evasion,persistence,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1056</id>
			<id>T1056.001</id>
			<id>T1556</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: This refers to a security mechanism that allows access to systems or applications based on specific keywords that trigger alerts for potential keylogging activity. Keyloggers, malicious tools designed to capture and record keystrokes, pose a significant threat to sensitive data, such as passwords, personal information, and financial details. By implementing keyword-based detection, the system monitors user inputs and flags suspicious patterns or keywords that might indicate the presence of a keylogger. Once a match is detected, the system can either alert security teams, restrict access, or initiate defensive measures, preventing further compromise. This proactive detection method helps in identifying keylogging attempts early, protecting critical information from being captured by unauthorized parties and enhancing the overall security posture of the network. 
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104714" level="1">
		<if_sid>104704</if_sid>
		<field name="disposition_code" type="pcre2">^1027$</field>
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^68$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Access to financial data and services has been blocked.</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1071,T1071.001,T1203,command-and-control,execution,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
			<id>T1071.001</id>
			<id>T1203</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: The message "Access to financial data and services has been blocked" indicates that a user or device has been prevented from reaching websites or online platforms that provide financial information or services, such as banking sites, investment platforms, or payment gateways. This action is typically taken as a precautionary measure to protect users and the organization from potential security threats, such as phishing attacks, malware infections, or data breaches. By blocking access, the system aims to mitigate risks associated with accessing potentially harmful sites that could compromise sensitive financial information. It also ensures compliance with internal security policies and regulatory requirements. Users affected by this restriction may need to consult with their IT department or network administrator to understand the reasons for the block and seek appropriate access if necessary. 
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104715" level="1">
		<if_sid>104704</if_sid>
		<!-- <action type="pcre2">blocked</action> -->
		<field name="disposition_code" type="pcre2">^1029$</field>
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^74$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Blocking proxy avoidance to enhance network security.</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1090,T1071,command-and-control,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1090</id>
			<id>T1071</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: "Blocking Proxy Avoidance to Enhance Network Security" involves implementing strategies to prevent users from bypassing security measures through the use of proxy servers or similar tools. When users employ these proxies, they can access restricted websites and services, which can lead to significant security vulnerabilities, including exposure to malware, phishing attacks, and unauthorized data access. By actively blocking proxy avoidance, organizations can maintain tighter control over their network traffic and ensure that all data transfers are subject to monitoring and filtering. This not only protects sensitive information but also aids in regulatory compliance and reduces the risk of data breaches. Moreover, it enhances overall network performance by minimizing unauthorized usage that can drain bandwidth. 
	</info>
	</rule>
	<!-- <rule id="104713" level="9"><if_sid>104702</if_sid><field name="category_number" type="pcre2">74</field><description>Forcepoint Proxy - Blocking proxy avoidance to enhance network security.</description><group>s-a,medium,one-on-one,T1090,T1071,command-and-control,</group><mitre><id>T1090</id><id>T1071</id></mitre><info type="text">Description: "Blocking Proxy Avoidance to Enhance Network Security" involves implementing strategies to prevent users from bypassing security measures through the use of proxy servers or similar tools. When users employ these proxies, they can access restricted websites and services, which can lead to significant security vulnerabilities, including exposure to malware, phishing attacks, and unauthorized data access. By actively blocking proxy avoidance, organizations can maintain tighter control over their network traffic and ensure that all data transfers are subject to monitoring and filtering. This not only protects sensitive information but also aids in regulatory compliance and reduces the risk of data breaches. Moreover, it enhances overall network performance by minimizing unauthorized usage that can drain bandwidth. 
	</info></rule> -->
	<rule id="104716" level="1">  
		<if_sid>104703</if_sid>
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^220$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Access to compromised websites is permitted.</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1071,T1071.001,T1102,command-and-control,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
			<id>T1071.001</id>
			<id>T1102</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: Allowing access to compromised websites presents significant security risks and should only be considered under strict controlled conditions for specific security research or incident response purposes. Such access must be governed by a robust security framework that includes isolated virtual environments, detailed logging mechanisms, and advanced threat monitoring systems to track all interactions with compromised sites. Security professionals accessing these sites should use dedicated research systems disconnected from the main network, employ multiple layers of protection including VPNs, malware analysis tools, and network monitoring solutions, and maintain detailed documentation of all activities and findings. Access should be restricted to authorized security personnel only, requiring formal approval processes and risk assessments before granting permissions. All data collected during these interactions must be carefully analyzed for potential threats, stored securely, and used to enhance the organization's threat intelligence and defense mechanisms. Additionally, regular security audits should be conducted to ensure the isolation measures remain effective and no malicious code has escaped the containment systems. It's crucial to establish clear protocols for handling any security incidents that may arise during these authorized access sessions, including immediate response procedures and containment strategies. 
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104717" level="1">  
		<if_sid>104703</if_sid>
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^149$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - File type permitted for private IP addresses.</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1190,T1036,initial-access,defense-evasion,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1190</id>
			<id>T1036</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: File type permitted for private IP addresses refers to the specific types of files that are allowed to be transferred or accessed within a network environment that uses private IP addresses. Private IP addresses are typically used within an internal network, such as a company's intranet, and are not routable on the public internet. This restriction ensures that only certain file types, such as documents or images, can be exchanged within the secure network, reducing the risk of malicious files being introduced from external sources. By permitting only approved file types, organizations can maintain tighter control over the types of content that enter and exit the network, minimizing the risk of malware infections or unauthorized data access. This policy is important for securing internal communications and maintaining the integrity of the organization's private network while ensuring that necessary business operations involving file exchanges can continue securely. 
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104718" level="1">  
		<if_sid>104703</if_sid>
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^201$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Web collaboration tools permitted by policy exception.</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1071,T1071.001,command-and-control,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
			<id>T1071.001</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: This refers to the specific approval granted for using web-based collaboration platforms, despite these tools normally being restricted or prohibited by the organization’s standard security policies. This exception is often made to accommodate essential business needs, such as remote teamwork, project management, or real-time communication, where collaboration platforms like Zoom, Microsoft Teams, or Google Workspace are critical. However, such permissions are typically controlled and monitored to mitigate risks, ensuring that the use of these tools does not expose the organization to potential vulnerabilities such as data breaches or unauthorized access. This policy exception enables employees to work effectively while maintaining a balance between productivity and security compliance. 
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104719" level="1">
		<if_sid>104704</if_sid>
		<!-- <action type="pcre2">blocked</action> -->
		<field name="disposition_code" type="pcre2">^1054$</field>
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^99$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Downloads for application and software blocked with confirm option.</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T0843,T1071,command-and-control,lateral-movement,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T0843</id>
			<id>T1071</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: Downloads for application and software blocked with confirm option indicates that the system has identified a download attempt for an application or software, but due to security policies, it has been blocked temporarily. This block is in place to prevent potentially harmful or unauthorized software from being installed on the system. However, the user is presented with the option to confirm the action, allowing them to override the block if they believe the download is safe. This type of security measure ensures that users are aware of potential risks associated with downloading software, providing an additional layer of protection against malware, spyware, or unauthorized applications. 
	</info>
	</rule>
	<!-- use csae -->
	<rule id="104720" level="1">  
		<if_sid>104703</if_sid>
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^154$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Detect authorized responses to spyware threats</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1204,T1204.001,execution,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1204</id>
			<id>T1204.001</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: "Detecting Authorized Responses to Spyware Threats" involves identifying and taking appropriate action when spyware, a type of malicious software designed to secretly collect information from a user’s system, is detected. The first authorized response is to isolate the affected system to prevent further data collection. Security teams then use specialized tools to scan and identify the spyware on the system. Once detected, the spyware is removed through antivirus or anti-malware software. In cases where sensitive data may have been compromised, passwords, and account credentials are reset, and any affected systems are checked for additional vulnerabilities. The system is updated with the latest security patches to close any gaps that allowed the spyware to infiltrate. If the threat is significant, further investigation is conducted to understand how the spyware entered the network and whether there is any ongoing risk. Finally, authorized personnel may enhance monitoring on affected systems and train users on recognizing suspicious activities to reduce the chances of future spyware infections.
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104721" level="1">
		<if_sid>104704</if_sid>
		<!-- <action type="pcre2">blocked</action> -->
		<field name="disposition_code" type="pcre2">^1027$|^1028$</field>
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^6$|^13$|^66$|^22$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Detect user access to high risk restricted site.</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,soar-alert,T1566,T1566.002,initial-access,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1566</id>
			<id>T1566.002</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: The "Detect user access to high-risk restricted sites" involves using security tools to monitor attempts by users to visit websites flagged as potentially dangerous. These sites could pose cybersecurity threats by hosting malware, phishing schemes, or illegal content. Organizations typically employ threat intelligence feeds and advanced filtering technologies to detect and prevent access to these sites, automatically blocking them or triggering alerts for security teams. By doing so, businesses can protect their networks from data breaches, safeguard sensitive information, and ensure compliance with security policies. This proactive approach mitigates risks before they can affect system integrity or expose vulnerabilities. 
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104722" level="1">
		<if_sid>104704</if_sid>
		<!-- <action type="pcre2">blocked</action> -->
		<field name="disposition_code" type="pcre2">^1027$</field>
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^109$|^5$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Potential user access to blocked website.</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1071,command-and-control,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: This refers to a security mechanism designed to monitor and identify attempts by users to reach websites that have been restricted by organizational policies or security protocols. Blocked websites are typically categorized as high-risk, potentially harmful, or inappropriate for corporate environments. These sites may include malicious domains, phishing sites, or unauthorized content that could compromise the integrity of a network or expose it to cyber threats. By detecting such access attempts, the security system can log the incident, notify administrators, and prevent the user from interacting with the site. 
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104723" level="1">   
		<if_sid>104703</if_sid>
		<!--<action type="pcre2">blocked</action>-->
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^164$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Authorized actions for phishing and fraud cases.</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1024,T1566,T1566.001,execution,initial-access,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1024</id>
			<id>T1566</id>
			<id>T1566.001</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: Authorized Actions for Phishing and Fraud Cases refer to the formal procedures an organization follows when addressing confirmed phishing or fraudulent incidents. These actions typically start with verifying the nature of the attack through incident detection systems or user reports. Once confirmed, the organization isolates the affected systems or accounts to contain the threat. Authorized actions also involve immediate communication with internal stakeholders, including IT teams, legal departments, and management, to ensure a coordinated response. Security teams may then block malicious IP addresses, revoke compromised credentials, and deploy technical controls such as email filters or firewalls. Simultaneously, external authorities such as law enforcement or cybersecurity agencies may be involved if necessary. Finally, post-incident analysis is conducted to evaluate the response’s effectiveness, identify security gaps, and update policies to prevent similar future incidents.  
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104724" level="1">   
		<if_sid>104703</if_sid>
		<!-- <field name="disposition_code" type="pcre2">^1045$|^1301$</field> -->
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^115$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Potential user consuming large amount of bandwidth.</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1071,T1071.001,T1071.004,command-and-control,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
			<id>T1071.001</id>
			<id>T1071.004</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: Detecting a user consuming a large amount of bandwidth is a critical cybersecurity practice to identify potential threats or abnormal network activity. Excessive bandwidth usage can be an indicator of malicious activities, such as data exfiltration, Distributed Denial-of-Service (DDoS) attacks, or botnet operations, where compromised devices are used to send vast amounts of data. In corporate environments, large bandwidth consumption can also flag insider threats, like employees uploading sensitive data to unauthorized locations. Monitoring such patterns allows network administrators to spot unusual spikes in traffic, helping prevent security breaches and maintaining optimal network performance 
	</info>
	</rule>
	

	<rule id="104733" level="1">
		<if_sid>104703</if_sid>
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^207$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Detect authorized access to suspicious embedded link is permitted.</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1204,T1204.001,execution,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1204</id>
			<id>T1204.001</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: Detecting authorized access to suspicious embedded links requires a comprehensive monitoring and validation framework while maintaining controlled permissions for legitimate business needs. The system must implement sophisticated link analysis tools that scan for malicious patterns, suspicious redirects, and known threat indicators while maintaining a whitelist of approved access scenarios for authorized personnel. Real-time monitoring should track user interactions with embedded links, logging access patterns, analyzing click-through behaviors, and validating link destinations against threat intelligence databases. Access permissions should be role-based, requiring multi-factor authentication and proper documentation of the business justification for accessing flagged links. The framework must maintain detailed audit trails of all interactions, including timestamp, user identity, link destination, and access context, while automated alerts should trigger when suspicious patterns or unauthorized access attempts are detected. Additionally, regular security assessments should evaluate the effectiveness of detection mechanisms and update policies based on emerging threats.
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104734" level="1">
		<if_sid>104703</if_sid>
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^213$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Detect responses to potentially exploited documents</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1204,T1204.002,execution,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1204</id>
			<id>T1204.002</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: Detecting responses to potentially exploited documents involves monitoring for suspicious activities triggered by opening malicious files, such as Word or PDF documents, that could exploit software vulnerabilities. These documents may contain malicious code designed to gain unauthorized access, execute commands, or drop malware on the victim’s system. Security solutions track behavior like abnormal process execution, unauthorized system changes, or network communications initiated by the document. The goal is to identify exploitation attempts early by correlating these actions with known attack patterns, alerting defenders before significant damage is done, and mitigating potential risks. This process is crucial for defending against spear-phishing attacks and document-based malware campaigns.
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104735" level="1">
		<if_sid>104703</if_sid>
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^214$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Detect potential access to mobile malware</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,T1658,execution,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1658</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: Detecting potential access to mobile malware involves identifying behaviors and indicators that suggest a mobile device may be compromised. Mobile malware can exploit vulnerabilities or use social engineering tactics to infiltrate a device, often through malicious apps, SMS messages, or web downloads. Indicators include unusual app permissions, high battery usage, excessive data consumption, or the presence of unrecognized apps. Security systems monitor network traffic, application behavior, and file integrity to detect malware attempting to gain access to sensitive information, control the device, or spread to other devices. Early detection helps prevent data theft, spying, or the loss of personal and corporate information.
		</info>
	</rule>

	<rule id="104736" level="1">
		<if_sid>104703</if_sid>
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^217$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Detect authorized access to files containing passwords</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1552,T1552.001,credential-access,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1552</id>
			<id>T1552.001</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: Detecting authorized access to files containing passwords involves monitoring legitimate but sensitive activities where users or systems access files storing credentials. While access may be permitted, such files are highly sensitive and could be targeted by attackers. Security measures track authorized users' interactions with these files, such as file openings, modifications, or copies, while ensuring that these accesses comply with predefined policies. Alerts may be triggered when unusual access patterns arise, such as accessing the file outside of normal business hours, from unusual locations, or by users with no prior history of such access. Detecting and auditing these actions ensures proper use, preventing credential exposure and insider threats.
		</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104737" level="1">
		<if_sid>104703</if_sid>
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^218$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Detection of permitted advanced malware command and control activity</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1204,T1059,execution,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1204</id>
			<id>T1059</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: Detection of permitted advanced malware Command and Control (C2) activity involves identifying malicious communication that is allowed to occur within a compromised environment, often by masquerading as legitimate traffic. Advanced malware can establish C2 channels to receive instructions from attackers, exfiltrate data, or expand its foothold within the network. These channels may be encrypted, hidden in legitimate services, or blend into normal traffic, making detection difficult. Security tools focus on behavioral anomalies, such as unusual outbound traffic patterns, long-lasting connections, or unexpected encrypted communications. Detecting this activity is critical for stopping malware from performing harmful actions, such as data theft, lateral movement, or system sabotage, despite it being masked as legitimate.
		</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104738" level="1">
		<if_sid>104703</if_sid>
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^205$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Detect potential access to malicious embedded link is permitted.</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1204,T1204.001,execution,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1204</id>
			<id>T1204.001</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: Detecting potential access to malicious embedded links that is permitted involves monitoring for instances where users or systems access harmful URLs embedded in emails, documents, or websites, despite the link being allowed through initial security layers. Attackers often use these links in phishing or social engineering campaigns to direct victims to exploit kits, malware downloads, or fraudulent sites designed to steal credentials. Security systems track click-through activities, analyze the reputation of accessed URLs, and monitor resulting behaviors, such as file downloads or abnormal network traffic. By identifying suspicious link accesses, even when permitted, security teams can mitigate risks before further compromise, such as malware execution or credential theft, occurs.
		</info>
	</rule>

	<rule id="104741" level="1">
		<if_sid>104703</if_sid>
		<field name="category_number" type="pcre2">^200$</field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Authorized detection of potential access to web and email spam</description>
		<group>medium,one-on-one,soar-alert,T1566,T1566.002,initial-access,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1566</id>
			<id>T1566.002</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: Detect potential access of web and email spam is permitted refers to allowing systems to monitor and identify instances where users or entities might interact with spam content via the web or email. This detection capability is essential in cybersecurity, as spam is often a vector for phishing attacks, malware distribution, and other malicious activities. By enabling detection, organizations can proactively track and analyze spam-related interactions to prevent threats before they escalate. Early detection helps mitigate risks such as data breaches, unauthorized access, or system compromise. Monitoring spam access also provides valuable insights into potential security vulnerabilities, ultimately enhancing protection against cyberattacks hidden within spam communications and safeguarding network environments.
		</info>
	</rule>

<rule id="104725" level="2" frequency="5" timeframe="3600">
		<if_matched_sid>104724</if_matched_sid>
		<same_field>tenant</same_field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Multiple instances of high bandwidth usage detected from potential user.</description>
		<group>medium,aggregation,s-a,T1071,T1071.001,T1071.004,command-and-control,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
			<id>T1071.001</id>
			<id>T1071.004</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: A network monitoring system has flagged unusual spikes in bandwidth consumption by a user or group of users, signaling a potential security incident. This behavior could indicate data exfiltration, where large volumes of sensitive data are being transferred out of the organization without authorization. Alternatively, the high bandwidth usage could be symptomatic of malware or a botnet infection, where compromised systems are being used to carry out Distributed Denial-of-Service (DDoS) attacks or other malicious activities. Anomalous network usage patterns like this require immediate investigation to determine if the user’s credentials or systems have been compromised, and to mitigate any risks of data loss or further infiltration by threat actors. Proactive analysis and correlation with threat intelligence are essential to understand if this is part of a larger attack or isolated behavior. 
	</info>
	</rule>
	<rule id="104726" level="2" frequency="5" timeframe="3600">
		<if_matched_sid>104722</if_matched_sid>
		<same_field>tenant</same_field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Repeated unauthorized access attempts to blocked website.</description>
		<group>medium,aggregation,s-a,T1071,command-and-control,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1071</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: Repeated unauthorized access attempts to blocked website refers to a cybersecurity incident where an individual or entity persistently tries to access a restricted or blacklisted web domain. This activity could be an indicator of malicious intent, such as an attempt to bypass network security controls, probe for vulnerabilities, or execute a potential attack. The persistence of these attempts often signals that automated tools or bots are being used to circumvent defenses. These actions may lead to potential security risks, such as data exfiltration or malware infiltration, if successful. Monitoring these repeated access attempts is crucial for detecting potential breaches and strengthening firewall or content filtering policies to mitigate further risks. 
	</info>
	</rule>

	<rule id="104739" level="2" frequency="5" timeframe="60">
		<if_matched_sid>104736</if_matched_sid>
		<same_field>tenant</same_field>
		<description>Forcepoint Proxy - Repeated unauthorized attempts to access files containing passwords</description>
		<group>medium,aggregation,s-a,T1552,T1552.001,credential-access,</group>
		<mitre>
			<id>T1552</id>
			<id>T1552.001</id>
		</mitre>
		<info type="text">Description: Repeated unauthorized attempts to access files containing passwords indicate a potential brute force or targeted attack on sensitive information. Attackers may repeatedly attempt to access these files using various methods, such as exploiting weak passwords, stolen credentials, or automated tools to bypass security controls. Monitoring systems detect these attempts by tracking abnormal login behaviors, such as multiple failed login attempts or access requests from unfamiliar IP addresses or devices. Alerts are generated when these attempts exceed predefined thresholds, allowing for swift intervention to block further unauthorized access, enhance password policies, or investigate the source of the attack. Early detection helps prevent unauthorized access to critical credentials and safeguards sensitive data. 
	</info>
	</rule>
	
</group>
