<!--

Test Upload


Rule ID Range: 100000 - 100599
Last Rule used: 100113
Unused Rule ID:100039,100040,100087,100088,100090,100013,100014,100015,100016,100099,100100,100107,100109,100112,100114
-->

<group name="paloalto,">

<!-- <rule id="64500" level="0" overwrite="yes" noalert="1">
   <decoded_as>paloalto-custom</decoded_as>
   <description>PaloAlto Rules.</description>
   <group>info,one-on-one,</group>
</rule> -->

<!-- JSON Rule -->

<rule id="100036" level="0" noalert="1">
    <decoded_as>json</decoded_as> 
    <field name="productName" type="pcre2">(?i)PaloAlto</field>
    <description>PaloAlto Rules.</description>
   <group>info,one-on-one,</group>
</rule>

<rule id="100037" level="0" noalert="1">
    <if_sid>64500,100036</if_sid>
    <description>PaloAlto Rules.</description>
   <group>info,one-on-one,</group>
</rule>

<!--Custom Rules-->

<rule id="100000" level="0" noalert="1">
   <if_sid>100037</if_sid>
   <field name="log_type" type="pcre2">(?i)TRAFFIC</field>
   <description>PaloAlto: Traffic Log.</description>
   <group>info,one-on-one,</group>
</rule>

<rule id="100001" level="0" noalert="1">
   <if_sid>100037</if_sid>
   <field name="log_type" type="pcre2">(?i)THREAT</field>
   <description>PaloAlto: Threat Log.</description>
   <group>info,one-on-one,</group>
</rule>

<rule id="100002" level="0" noalert="1">
   <if_sid>100037</if_sid>
   <field name="log_type" type="pcre2">(?i)URL\s+Filtering</field>
   <description>PaloAlto: URL filtering Log.</description>
   <group>info,one-on-one,</group>
</rule>

<rule id="100003" level="0" noalert="1">
   <if_sid>100037</if_sid>
   <field name="log_type" type="pcre2">(?i)Data\s+Filtering</field>
   <description>PaloAlto: Data filtering Log.</description>
   <group>info,one-on-one,</group>
</rule>

<rule id="100004" level="0" noalert="1">
   <if_sid>100037</if_sid>
   <field name="log_type" type="pcre2">(?i)HIPMATCH</field>
   <description>PaloAlto: HIP Match Log.</description>
   <group>info,one-on-one,</group>
</rule>

<rule id="100005" level="0" noalert="1">
   <if_sid>100037</if_sid>
   <field name="log_type" type="pcre2">(?i)GLOBALPROTECT</field>
   <description>PaloAlto: GlobalProtect Log.</description>
   <group>info,one-on-one,</group>
</rule>

<rule id="100006" level="0" noalert="1">
   <if_sid>100037</if_sid>
   <field name="log_type" type="pcre2">(?i)IPTAG</field>
   <description>PaloAlto: IP-Tag Log.</description>
   <group>info,one-on-one,</group>
</rule>

<rule id="100007" level="0" noalert="1">
   <if_sid>100037</if_sid>
   <field name="log_type" type="pcre2">(?i)USERID</field>
   <description>PaloAlto: User-ID Log.</description>
   <group>info,one-on-one,</group>
</rule>

<rule id="100008" level="0" noalert="1">
   <if_sid>100037</if_sid>
   <field name="log_type" type="pcre2">(?i)SCTP</field>
   <description>PaloAlto: SCTP Log.</description>
   <group>info,one-on-one,</group>
</rule>

<rule id="100009" level="0" noalert="1">
   <if_sid>100037</if_sid>
   <field name="log_type" type="pcre2">(?i)AUTH</field>
   <description>PaloAlto: Authentication Log.</description>
   <group>info,one-on-one,</group>
</rule>

<rule id="100010" level="0" noalert="1">
   <if_sid>100037</if_sid>
   <field name="log_type" type="pcre2">(?i)CONFIG</field>
   <description>PaloAlto: Config Log.</description>
   <group>info,one-on-one,</group>
</rule>

<rule id="100011" level="0" noalert="1">
   <if_sid>100037</if_sid>
   <field name="log_type" type="pcre2">(?i)SYSTEM</field>
   <description>PaloAlto: System Log.</description>
   <group>info,one-on-one,</group>
</rule>

<rule id="100012" level="0" noalert="1">
   <if_sid>100037</if_sid>
   <field name="log_type" type="pcre2">(?i)CORRELATION</field>
   <description>PaloAlto: Correlated Event Log.</description>
   <group>info,one-on-one,</group>
</rule>
 
 <rule id="100089" level="0" noalert="1">
    <if_sid>100003</if_sid>
    <field name="log_subtype" type="pcre2">(?i)dlp</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Data loss prevention rule.</description>
   <group>info,one-on-one,</group>
</rule> 

<rule id="100017" level="1" noalert="1">
    <if_sid>100001,100005</if_sid>
    <field name="log_subtype" type="pcre2">(?i)data</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Data pattern matching a Data Filtering profile was detected.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,T1029,policy,violation,exfiltration,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: This rule identifies sessions where data pattern matching triggered a Data Filtering profile, indicating potential attempts to transfer restricted or sensitive data.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1029</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>  

<rule id="100018" level="1">
    <if_sid>100017</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)low</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A data pattern matched a Data Filtering profile with a low severity level.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,T1029,policy,violation,exfiltration,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The rule identifies sessions where a data pattern matched a Data Filtering profile categorized with a low severity level, suggesting a minor policy violation or less critical data transfer attempts.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1029</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100019" level="1">
    <if_sid>100017</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)medium</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A data pattern matched a Data Filtering profile with a medium severity level.</description>
    <group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,policy,violation,exfiltration,T1029,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The rule identifies sessions where a data pattern matched a Data Filtering profile categorized with a medium severity level, indicating a moderate risk of unauthorized data transfer.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1029</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100020" level="1">
    <if_sid>100017</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)high</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A data pattern matched a Data Filtering profile with a high severity level.</description>
    <group>high,one-on-one,s-a,T1040,T1005,credential-access,policy,violation,command-and-control,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: This rule triggers when a data pattern matches a Data Filtering profile with a high severity level, indicating a critical breach of data policies and the potential exposure of sensitive information.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1040</id>
        <id>T1005</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100021" level="1">
    <if_sid>100017</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)critical</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A data pattern matched a Data Filtering profile with a critical severity level.</description>
    <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,T1071,command-and-control,T1040,policy,violation,credential-access,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The rule triggers when a data pattern matches a Data Filtering profile with a critical severity level, indicating a high-risk transfer involving sensitive or classified information.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1071</id>
        <id>T1040</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>
 
<rule id="100022" level="1" noalert="1">
    <if_sid>100001,100005</if_sid>
    <field name="log_subtype" type="pcre2">(?i)file</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A file type was detected that matches a File Blocking profile.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,block,T1213,collection,T1203,execution,policy,violation,T1204.002,T1204,execution</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: This rule triggers when a file type is detected that matches a File Blocking profile, suggesting an attempt to transfer or access a restricted file type according to policy.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1213</id>
        <id>T1203</id>
        <id>T1204.002</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100023" level="1">
    <if_sid>100022</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)low</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A file type was detected that matches a File Blocking profile with a low severity level.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,block,T1213,collection,T1203,execution,policy,violation,T1204.002,T1204,execution</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: This rule indicates that a restricted or undesirable file type has been identified, but the associated risk is considered minimal, suggesting a minor policy violation.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1213</id>
        <id>T1203</id>
        <id>T1204.002</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100024" level="1">
    <if_sid>100022</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)medium</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A file type was detected that matches a File Blocking profile with a medium severity level.</description>
    <group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1041,exfiltration,T1204.002,T1204,execution,block,policy,violation,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: This rule indicates that a restricted file type has been detected, posing a moderate risk that may require further investigation or attention.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1041</id>
        <id>T1204.002</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100025" level="1">
    <if_sid>100022</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)high</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A file type was detected that matches a File Blocking profile with a high severity level.</description>
    <group>high,one-on-one,s-a,T1041,exfiltration,T1204.002,T1204,execution,block,policy,violation,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of a file type matching a File Blocking profile with a high severity level indicates a potential security threat requiring immediate attention to prevent unauthorized access or data exfiltration.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1041</id>
        <id>T1204.002</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100026" level="1">
    <if_sid>100022</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)critical</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A file type was detected that matches a File Blocking profile with a critical severity level.</description>
    <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,T1041,exfiltration,T1204.002,T1204,execution,block,policy,violation,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: This rule signifies an urgent and severe security threat involving a highly sensitive file type that has been detected, necessitating immediate investigation and remediation.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1041</id>
        <id>T1204.002</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100027" level="1" noalert="1">
    <if_sid>100001,100005</if_sid>
    <field name="log_subtype" type="pcre2">(?i)flood</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A flood was detected through a Zone Protection profile.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,detect,flood,T1499,impact,T1498,dos,ddos,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of a flood through a Zone Protection profile indicates an abnormal surge in traffic or requests targeting a specific network zone, which could overwhelm and disrupt services. This type of attack, often referred to as a denial-of-service (DoS) or distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attack, aims to exhaust system resources and degrade performance.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1499</id>
        <id>T1498</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100028" level="1">
    <if_sid>100027</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)low</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A flood was detected through a Zone Protection profile with a low severity level.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,detect,flood,T1499,impact,T1498,dos,ddos,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of a flood through a Zone Protection profile with a low severity level indicates a minor, yet notable increase in traffic within a specific network zone. While this level of flood may not currently pose a significant threat, it could be an early sign of potential issues or attempts to probe network defenses. It's important to monitor the situation closely, assess traffic patterns, and ensure that Zone Protection settings are appropriately configured.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1499</id>
        <id>T1498</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100029" level="1">
    <if_sid>100027</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)medium</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A flood was detected through a Zone Protection profile with a medium severity level.</description>
    <group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,detect,flood,T1499,impact,T1498,dos,ddos,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of a flood through a Zone Protection profile with a medium severity level signifies a notable increase in traffic that could impact the performance or stability of the affected network zone. This level of flood suggests a moderate risk of service disruption or system overload, potentially due to malicious intent or a misconfiguration. It’s important to analyze the traffic to identify patterns, apply mitigation measures such as rate limiting and traffic filtering, and adjust Zone Protection settings as necessary.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1499</id>
        <id>T1498</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100030" level="1">
    <if_sid>100027</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)high</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A flood was detected through a Zone Protection profile with a high severity level.</description>
    <group>high,one-on-one,s-a,detect,flood,T1499,impact,T1498,dos,ddos,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of a flood through a Zone Protection profile with a high severity level indicates a significant and potentially disruptive surge in traffic targeting a specific network zone. This severe level of flood could be indicative of an active denial-of-service (DoS) or distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attack aimed at overwhelming network resources and causing substantial service degradation. Immediate action is critical—implement advanced traffic filtering, enhance rate limiting, and possibly engage with upstream providers for additional support.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1499</id>
        <id>T1498</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100031" level="1">
    <if_sid>100027</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)critical</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A flood was detected through a Zone Protection profile with a critical severity level.</description>
    <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,detect,flood,T1499,impact,T1498,dos,ddos,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of a flood through a Zone Protection profile with a critical severity level signifies a severe and potentially catastrophic surge in traffic that is overwhelming the network zone. This high level of flood is likely indicative of an intense denial-of-service (DoS) or distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attack, aiming to disrupt or completely halt network operations. Immediate and decisive action is required: implement emergency traffic mitigation strategies, engage with external support if needed, and assess the impact on critical services.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1499</id>
        <id>T1498</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100032" level="1" noalert="1">
    <if_sid>100001,100005</if_sid>
    <field name="log_subtype" type="pcre2">(?i)packet</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Packet-based attack protection was activated by a Zone Protection profile.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,attack,T1040,credential-access,T1071.001,T1071,command-and-control,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The activation of packet-based attack protection by a Zone Protection profile indicates that the security system has detected and responded to an attempt to exploit vulnerabilities through malicious packet traffic. This typically involves measures like filtering, rate limiting, or blocking specific types of packets to mitigate attacks such as network floods, fragmentation attacks, or protocol exploits.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1040</id>
        <id>T1071</id>
        <id>T1071.001</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100033" level="1">
    <if_sid>100032</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)low</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Packet-based attack protection was triggered by a Zone Protection profile with a low severity level.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,attack,T1040,credential-access,T1071.001,T1071,command-and-control,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The triggering of packet-based attack protection by a Zone Protection profile with a low severity level indicates that the system has detected and mitigated a minor packet-based threat. This typically involves handling lower-level attacks or anomalies in packet traffic that do not currently pose a significant risk.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1040</id>
        <id>T1071</id>
        <id>T1071.001</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100034" level="1">
    <if_sid>100032</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)medium</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Packet-based attack protection was triggered by a Zone Protection profile with a medium severity level.</description>
    <group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,attack,T1040,credential-access,T1071.001,T1071,command-and-control,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The triggering of packet-based attack protection by a Zone Protection profile with a medium severity level indicates a moderate threat where malicious or abnormal packet traffic has been detected and blocked. This suggests a potential attempt to exploit vulnerabilities or disrupt network services through packet manipulation.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1040</id>
        <id>T1071</id>
        <id>T1071.001</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100035" level="1">
    <if_sid>100032</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)high</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Packet-based attack protection was triggered by a Zone Protection profile with a high severity level.</description>
    <group>high,one-on-one,s-a,attack,T1040,credential-access,T1071.001,T1071,command-and-control,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The triggering of packet-based attack protection by a Zone Protection profile with a high severity level indicates a significant threat where a substantial volume or intensity of malicious packet traffic has been detected. This level of protection activation suggests a serious attempt to exploit network vulnerabilities or disrupt services, potentially through sophisticated attack vectors.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1040</id>
        <id>T1071</id>
        <id>T1071.001</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

 <rule id="100038" level="1">
    <if_sid>100032</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)critical</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Packet-based attack protection was triggered by a Zone Protection profile with a critical severity level.</description>
    <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,attack,T1040,credential-access,T1071.001,T1071,command-and-control,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The triggering of packet-based attack protection by a Zone Protection profile with a critical severity level indicates an extreme and potentially catastrophic packet-based attack. This level of activation suggests a highly aggressive attempt to overwhelm or disrupt network services through intense and sustained malicious traffic.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1040</id>
        <id>T1071</id>
        <id>T1071.001</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100041" level="1" noalert="1">
    <if_sid>100001,100005</if_sid>
    <field name="log_subtype" type="pcre2">(?i)scan</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Scan detected via a Zone Protection profile.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,detect,recon,T1595,reconnaissance,T1046,discovery,T1595.002,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of a scan via a Zone Protection profile indicates that the security system has identified reconnaissance activities targeting the network. Such scans often involve probing for vulnerabilities or gathering information about network configuration and exposed services. While this activity might not be immediately harmful, it is a precursor to potential attacks.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1595</id>
        <id>T1046</id>
        <id>T1595.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100042" level="1">
    <if_sid>100041</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)low</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Scan detected via a Zone Protection profile with a low severity level.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,detect,recon,T1595,reconnaissance,T1046,discovery,T1595.002,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of a scan via a Zone Protection profile with a low severity level indicates a minor reconnaissance activity that is not currently posing a significant threat. This level suggests that the scan might be a routine or non-malicious probing attempt, often used for routine assessments or benign testing.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1595</id>
        <id>T1046</id>
        <id>T1595.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100043" level="1">
    <if_sid>100041</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)medium</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Scan detected via a Zone Protection profile with a medium severity level.</description>
    <group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,detect,recon,T1595,reconnaissance,T1046,discovery,T1595.002,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of a scan via a Zone Protection profile with a medium severity level indicates a more significant reconnaissance effort that could suggest a higher potential for malicious intent. This level of detection implies that the scan is probing more aggressively or targeting critical network areas, which may be a precursor to a more serious attack.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1595</id>
        <id>T1046</id>
        <id>T1595.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>
  
<rule id="100044" level="1">
    <if_sid>100041</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)high</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Scan detected via a Zone Protection profile with a high severity level.</description>
    <group>high,one-on-one,s-a,detect,recon,T1595,reconnaissance,T1046,discovery,T1595.002,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of a scan via a Zone Protection profile with a high severity level signifies a serious reconnaissance effort that likely indicates a targeted and aggressive approach to probing network vulnerabilities. This level of scan suggests a high likelihood of malicious intent, potentially laying the groundwork for a significant attack or exploitation attempt.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1595</id>
        <id>T1046</id>
        <id>T1595.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100045" level="1">
    <if_sid>100041</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)critical</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Scan detected via a Zone Protection profile with a critical severity level.</description>
    <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,detect,recon,T1595,reconnaissance,T1046,discovery,T1595.002,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of a scan via a Zone Protection profile with a critical severity level indicates an intense and highly aggressive reconnaissance activity, likely part of a sophisticated and imminent attack strategy. This level suggests that the scan is targeting critical or sensitive areas of your network with the intent to identify and exploit vulnerabilities.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1595</id>
        <id>T1046</id>
        <id>T1595.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100046" level="1" noalert="1">
    <if_sid>100001,100005</if_sid>
    <field name="log_subtype" type="pcre2">(?i)spyware</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Spyware detected via an Anti-Spyware profile.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,detect,malware,T1587.001,T1587,resource-development,T1204,execution,T1588,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of spyware via an Anti-Spyware profile indicates that malicious software designed to monitor and collect sensitive information has been identified on your system. Spyware often operates stealthily to capture data such as keystrokes, browsing habits, or personal information, which can lead to privacy breaches or data theft.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1587</id>
        <id>T1587.001</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1588</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100047" level="1">
    <if_sid>100046</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)medium</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Spyware detected via an Anti-Spyware profile with a medium severity level.</description>
    <group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,detect,malware,T1587.001,T1587,resource-development,T1204,execution,T1588,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of spyware via an Anti-Spyware profile with a medium severity level suggests a moderate threat where spyware has been identified on the system, potentially impacting privacy or data security. This level of severity indicates that while the threat is concerning, it may not yet have caused significant harm or data loss. It is important to promptly quarantine or remove the spyware, conduct a detailed system scan to check for additional threats, and review the affected systems for any signs of compromise.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1587</id>
        <id>T1587.001</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1588</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100048" level="1">
    <if_sid>100046</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)high</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Spyware detected via an Anti-Spyware profile with a high severity level.</description>
    <group>high,one-on-one,s-a,detect,malware,T1587.001,T1587,resource-development,T1204,execution,T1588,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of spyware via an Anti-Spyware profile with a high severity level indicates a serious threat where highly intrusive spyware has been identified on the system. This level of severity suggests significant risk to privacy and data security, with potential for extensive data collection or unauthorized access. Immediate action is required: quarantine or remove the spyware, conduct a comprehensive system scan to identify and address any additional threats, and review logs for signs of data compromise.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1587</id>
        <id>T1587.001</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1588</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100049" level="1">
    <if_sid>100046</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)critical</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Spyware detected via an Anti-Spyware profile with a critical severity level.</description>
    <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,detect,malware,T1587.001,T1587,resource-development,T1204,execution,T1588,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of spyware via an Anti-Spyware profile with a critical severity level signifies an urgent and severe threat, indicating that highly damaging and potentially widespread spyware has been identified. This level suggests that the spyware could be actively exfiltrating sensitive data, compromising system integrity, or facilitating extensive unauthorized access.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1587</id>
        <id>T1587.001</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1588</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100050" level="1" noalert="1">
    <if_sid>100001,100005</if_sid>
    <field name="log_subtype" type="pcre2">(?i)url</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: URL filtering activity recorded.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,policy,violation,T1204.001,T1204,execution,T1071,command-and-control,T1566,initial-access,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The alert of "URL filtering activity" indicates that the system has detected and potentially blocked or monitored access to specific websites based on predefined security policies. URL filtering is typically used to prevent users from accessing malicious, inappropriate, or unauthorized websites that could pose security risks or violate company policies.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1566</id>
        <id>T1204.001</id>
        <id>T1071</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100051" level="1">
    <if_sid>100050</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)low</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: URL filtering activity with a low severity level.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,policy,violation,T1204.001,T1204,execution,T1071,command-and-control,T1566,initial-access,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: A "URL filtering log with a low severity level" indicates that the system has recorded an attempt to access a website that is deemed low risk but may still be restricted based on organizational policies. This could involve accessing non-malicious sites that are categorized as inappropriate, non-work-related, or potentially distracting. While the threat level is low, it's important to review these logs to ensure that the filtering policies are correctly applied and to identify any patterns in user behavior that may require attention.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1566</id>
        <id>T1204.001</id>
        <id>T1071</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100052" level="1">
    <if_sid>100050</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)medium</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: URL filtering activity with a medium severity level.</description>
    <group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,policy,violation,T1204.001,T1204,execution,T1071,command-and-control,T1566,initial-access,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: A "URL filtering log with a medium severity level" indicates that the system has detected and possibly blocked access to a website that poses a moderate risk. This could involve sites that are potentially harmful, such as those associated with adware, questionable content, or sites with a history of security vulnerabilities. Although the risk isn't critical, accessing such sites could still lead to exposure to malicious content or compromise network security.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1566</id>
        <id>T1204.001</id>
        <id>T1071</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100053" level="1">
    <if_sid>100050</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)high</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: URL filtering activity with a high severity level.</description>
    <group>high,one-on-one,s-a,policy,violation,T1204.001,T1204,execution,T1071,command-and-control,T1566,initial-access,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: A "URL filtering log with a high severity level" indicates that the system has detected and likely blocked an attempt to access a website that poses a significant security risk. This could involve sites associated with malware, phishing, illegal content, or known attack vectors. Such attempts could lead to severe security breaches, including data theft, system compromise, or exposure to harmful content.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1566</id>
        <id>T1204.001</id>
        <id>T1071</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100054" level="1">
    <if_sid>100050</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)critical</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: URL filtering log with a critical severity level.</description>
    <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,policy,violation,T1204.001,T1204,execution,T1071,command-and-control,T1566,initial-access,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: A "URL filtering log with a critical severity level" indicates that the system has detected and blocked an attempt to access a highly dangerous website that poses an extreme security threat. This could involve sites known for distributing advanced malware, orchestrating phishing campaigns, or hosting illegal content that could lead to immediate and severe consequences for the network and data security.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1566</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1204.001</id>
        <id>T1071</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100055" level="1" noalert="1">
    <if_sid>100001,100005</if_sid>
    <field name="log_subtype" type="pcre2">(?i)virus</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A virus was detected through an Antivirus profile.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,T1587.001,T1587,T1204.002,T1204,execution,resource-development,malicious,detect,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of a virus through an Antivirus profile indicates that malicious software has been identified on the system. This virus could potentially disrupt operations, compromise data, or spread to other systems if not addressed promptly. Immediate action should be taken to quarantine or remove the virus, followed by a thorough system scan to check for any additional threats.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1587</id>
        <id>T1587.001</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1204.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100056" level="1">
    <if_sid>100055</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)low</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A virus was detected through an Antivirus profile with a low severity level.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,T1587.001,T1587,T1204.002,T1204,execution,resource-development,malicious,detect,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of a virus through an Antivirus profile with a low severity level indicates that the system has identified malware that poses a relatively minor threat. This could involve older or less sophisticated viruses that are unlikely to cause significant damage or are easily contained by current security measures.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1587</id>
        <id>T1587.001</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1204.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100057" level="1">
    <if_sid>100055</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)medium</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A virus was detected through an Antivirus profile with a medium severity level.</description>
    <group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1587.001,T1587,T1204.002,T1204,execution,resource-development,malicious,detect,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of a virus through an Antivirus profile with a medium severity level indicates that a potentially harmful piece of malware has been identified on the system. This level of severity suggests that the virus could disrupt operations, compromise data, or spread within the network if not addressed.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1587</id>
        <id>T1587.001</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1204.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100058" level="1">
    <if_sid>100055</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)high</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A virus was detected through an Antivirus profile with a high severity level.</description>
    <group>high,one-on-one,s-a,T1587.001,T1587,T1204.002,T1204,execution,resource-development,malicious,detect,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of a virus via an Antivirus profile with a high severity level indicates the presence of a dangerous and potentially destructive piece of malware on the system. This level of severity suggests that the virus could cause significant harm, such as data loss, system corruption, or spreading rapidly across the network.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1587</id>
        <id>T1587.001</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1204.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100059" level="1">
    <if_sid>100055</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)critical</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A virus was detected through an Antivirus profile with a critical severity level.</description>
    <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,T1587.001,T1587,T1204.002,T1204,execution,resource-development,malicious,detect,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of a virus via an Antivirus profile with a critical severity level signifies an extremely serious threat to your system and network. This level of severity suggests that the virus is highly dangerous, capable of causing catastrophic damage, such as widespread data corruption, exfiltration of sensitive information, or total system compromise.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1587</id>
        <id>T1587.001</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1204.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100060" level="1" noalert="1">
    <if_sid>100001,100005</if_sid>
    <field name="log_subtype" type="pcre2">(?i)vulnerability</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A vulnerability exploit was detected through a Vulnerability Protection profile.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,vulnerability,detect,T1068,privilege-escalation,T1190,initial-access,T1588.006,resource-development,T1588,T1404,T1587,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of a vulnerability exploit through a Vulnerability Protection profile indicates that an attempt to exploit a known security weakness in the system has been identified. This could suggest that an attacker is trying to take advantage of a vulnerability to gain unauthorized access, escalate privileges, or execute malicious code.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1587</id>
        <id>T1404</id>
        <id>T1588</id>
        <id>T1190</id>
        <id>T1068</id>
        <id>T1588.006</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100061" level="1">
    <if_sid>100060</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)medium</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A vulnerability exploit was detected through a Vulnerability Protection profile with a medium severity level.</description>
    <group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,vulnerability,detect,T1068,privilege-escalation,T1190,initial-access,T1588.006,resource-development,T1588,T1404,T1587,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of a vulnerability exploit through a Vulnerability Protection profile with a medium severity level indicates a moderate risk where an attempt to exploit a known security weakness has been identified. This suggests that while the exploit may not be immediately catastrophic, it still poses a significant threat that could lead to unauthorized access or other security issues if not addressed.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1587</id>
        <id>T1404</id>
        <id>T1588</id>
        <id>T1190</id>
        <id>T1068</id>
        <id>T1588.006</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100062" level="1">
    <if_sid>100060</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)high</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A vulnerability exploit was detected through a Vulnerability Protection profile with a high severity level.</description>
    <group>high,one-on-one,s-a,vulnerability,detect,T1068,privilege-escalation,T1190,initial-access,T1588.006,resource-development,T1588,T1404,T1587,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of a vulnerability exploit through a Vulnerability Protection profile with a high severity level indicates a serious threat where an attempt to exploit a critical security weakness has been identified. This level of severity suggests that the exploit could have significant consequences, such as unauthorized access, data breaches, or system compromise.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1587</id>
        <id>T1404</id>
        <id>T1588</id>
        <id>T1190</id>
        <id>T1068</id>
        <id>T1588.006</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100063" level="1">
    <if_sid>100060</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)critical</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A vulnerability exploit was detected through a Vulnerability Protection profile with a critical severity level.</description>
    <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,vulnerability,detect,T1068,privilege-escalation,T1190,initial-access,T1588.006,resource-development,T1588,T1404,T1587,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of a vulnerability exploit through a Vulnerability Protection profile with a critical severity level indicates an extremely dangerous and urgent threat. This suggests that an attacker is attempting to exploit a highly severe vulnerability that could lead to catastrophic consequences, such as full system compromise, data exfiltration, or significant operational disruption.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1587</id>
        <id>T1404</id>
        <id>T1588</id>
        <id>T1190</id>
        <id>T1068</id>
        <id>T1588.006</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100064" level="1" noalert="1">
    <if_sid>100001,100005</if_sid>
    <field name="log_subtype" type="pcre2">(?i)wildfire</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: WildFire Verdict is generated when a firewall sends a file to a cloud-based malware analysis service to determine if it's malicious.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,sandbox,T1497,defense-evasion,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The WildFire Verdict is generated when a firewall sends a file to a cloud-based malware analysis service, such as Palo Alto Networks' WildFire, to determine its maliciousness. This verdict provides a classification of the file based on its behavior and characteristics observed during analysis. The verdict can indicate whether the file is benign, malicious, or if further investigation is needed.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1497</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100065" level="1">
    <if_sid>100064</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)medium</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: WildFire Verdict is generated when a firewall sends a file to a cloud-based malware analysis service to determine if it's malicious with a medium severity level.</description>
    <group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,sandbox,T1497,defense-evasion,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: A WildFire Verdict with a medium severity level is generated when a firewall sends a file to a cloud-based malware analysis service, and the analysis determines that the file poses a moderate risk. This indicates that while the file may not be immediately harmful, it could have the potential to cause issues if not addressed.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1497</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100066" level="1">
    <if_sid>100064</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)high</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: WildFire Verdict is generated when a firewall sends a file to a cloud-based malware analysis service to determine if it's malicious with a high severity level.</description>
    <group>high,one-on-one,s-a,sandbox,T1497,defense-evasion,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: A WildFire Verdict with a high severity level is generated when a firewall sends a file to a cloud-based malware analysis service, and the analysis determines that the file poses a significant threat. This indicates that the file is highly likely to be malicious and could have severe implications if executed, such as data breaches, system compromise, or widespread network impact.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1497</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100067" level="1">
    <if_sid>100064</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)critical</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: WildFire Verdict is generated when a firewall sends a file to a cloud-based malware analysis service to determine if it's malicious with a critical severity level.</description>
    <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,sandbox,T1497,defense-evasion,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: A WildFire Verdict is generated when a firewall sends a file to a cloud-based malware analysis service, which determines the file's potential maliciousness with a critical severity level. This verdict signifies that the file is highly likely to be malicious and poses a severe threat to the network and systems, such as ransomware, advanced persistent threats (APTs), or zero-day exploits.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1497</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100068" level="1" noalert="1">
    <if_sid>100001,100005</if_sid>
    <field name="log_subtype" type="pcre2">(?i)wildfire-virus</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A virus was detected through an Antivirus profile and categorized as a wildfire-virus.</description>
    <group>low,one-on-one,T1587.001,T1587,T1204.002,T1204,execution,resource-development,malicious,detect,sandbox,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: When a virus detected through an Antivirus profile is categorized as a "WildFire-virus," it means that the malware has been identified as a threat that has been analyzed and classified by a cloud-based malware analysis service, such as Palo Alto Networks' WildFire. This classification indicates that the virus has been recognized as a known malicious entity with potentially severe impacts.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1587</id>
        <id>T1587.001</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1204.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100069" level="1">
    <if_sid>100068</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)low</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A virus was detected through an Antivirus profile and categorized as a wildfire-virus with a low severity level.</description>
    <group>low,one-on-one,T1587.001,T1587,T1204.002,T1204,execution,resource-development,malicious,detect,sandbox,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: When a virus detected through an Antivirus profile is categorized as a "WildFire-virus" with a low severity level, it indicates that while the malware is identified as a known threat by the WildFire cloud-based analysis service, its immediate risk and impact are relatively minor.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1587</id>
        <id>T1587.001</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1204.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100070" level="1">
    <if_sid>100068</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)medium</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A virus was detected through an Antivirus profile and categorized as a wildfire-virus with a medium severity level.</description>
    <group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1587.001,T1587,T1204.002,T1204,execution,resource-development,malicious,detect,sandbox,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: When a virus detected through an Antivirus profile is categorized as a "WildFire-virus" with a medium severity level, it suggests that while the malware is recognized as a known threat by the WildFire cloud-based analysis service, its immediate risk is moderate. This implies that the virus could potentially cause harm or disrupt operations, but it is not currently deemed as critical.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1587</id>
        <id>T1587.001</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1204.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100071" level="1">
    <if_sid>100068</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)high</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A virus was detected through an Antivirus profile and categorized as a wildfire-virus with a high severity level.</description>
    <group>high,one-on-one,s-a,T1587.001,T1587,T1204.002,T1204,execution,resource-development,malicious,detect,sandbox,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: When a virus detected through an Antivirus profile is categorized as a "WildFire-virus" with a high severity level, it indicates that the malware is recognized as a significant threat by the WildFire cloud-based analysis service. This severity level suggests that the virus could cause substantial harm, such as compromising data, disrupting systems, or spreading rapidly within the network.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1587</id>
        <id>T1587.001</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1204.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100072" level="1">
    <if_sid>100068</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)critical</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A virus was detected through an Antivirus profile and categorized as a wildfire-virus with a critical severity level.</description>
    <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,T1587.001,T1587,T1204.002,T1204,execution,resource-development,malicious,detect,sandbox,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: When a virus detected through an Antivirus profile is categorized as a "WildFire-virus" with a critical severity level, it signifies that the malware is recognized as a highly dangerous threat by the WildFire cloud-based analysis service. This level indicates that the virus has the potential to cause severe damage, such as extensive data loss, system compromise, or widespread disruption.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1587</id>
        <id>T1587.001</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1204.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>  

<rule id="100073" level="1" noalert="1">
    <if_sid>100050</if_sid>
    <action>alert</action>
    <description>PaloAlto: A threat or URL was detected but not blocked.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,detect,T1204.001,T1204,execution,T1562.006,T1562,defense-evasion,T1566.002,T1566,initial-access,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: When a threat or URL is detected but not blocked, it indicates that the security system identified a potential risk but did not take action to prevent access or mitigate the threat. This could happen due to a policy setting that allows certain types of traffic through despite the detection, or it may be an indication of a misconfiguration.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1562.006</id>
        <id>T1204.001</id>
        <id>T1562</id>
        <id>T1566</id>
        <id>T1566.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100074" level="1">
    <if_sid>100073</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)medium</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A threat or URL was detected but not blocked with a medium severity level.</description>
   <group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,detect,T1204.001,T1204,execution,T1562.006,T1562,defense-evasion,T1566.002,T1566,initial-access,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: When a threat or URL with a medium severity level is detected but not blocked, it indicates that the security system has identified a potential risk that could have a moderate impact on the network or system but did not automatically prevent access. This could occur due to policy settings that allow certain medium-risk activities or an oversight in security configurations.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1562.006</id>
        <id>T1204.001</id>
        <id>T1562</id>
        <id>T1566</id>
        <id>T1566.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100075" level="1">
    <if_sid>100073</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)high</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A threat or URL was detected but not blocked with a high severity level.</description>
    <group>high,one-on-one,s-a,detect,T1204.001,T1204,execution,T1562.006,T1562,defense-evasion,T1566.002,T1566,initial-access,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: When a threat or URL with a high severity level is detected but not blocked, it indicates that a significant risk was identified, but the security system did not take action to prevent access or mitigate the threat. This situation is concerning because a high-severity threat could lead to serious consequences, such as data breaches, malware infections, or system compromise.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1562.006</id>
        <id>T1204.001</id>
        <id>T1562</id>
        <id>T1566</id>
        <id>T1566.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100076" level="1">
    <if_sid>100073</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)critical</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: A threat or URL was detected but not blocked with a critical severity level.</description>
    <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,detect,T1204.001,T1204,execution,T1562.006,T1562,defense-evasion,T1566.002,T1566,initial-access,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: When a threat or URL with a critical severity level is detected but not blocked, it signifies a major oversight or potential vulnerability in the security system. A critical threat typically represents the highest level of risk, with the potential to cause catastrophic damage, such as severe data breaches, widespread malware infections, or complete system compromise.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1562.006</id>
        <id>T1204.001</id>
        <id>T1562</id>
        <id>T1566</id>
        <id>T1566.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100077" level="1" noalert="1">
    <if_sid>100027</if_sid>
    <action>allow</action>
    <description>PaloAlto: Flood detection alert.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,T1499,impact,T1498.001,T1498,flood,detect,dos,ddos,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: A flood detection alert indicates that the system has identified a high volume of traffic directed at a specific network segment or resource, often in a very short period. This type of alert typically points to a potential Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) attack, where attackers attempt to overwhelm network resources, causing service disruption or complete downtime.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1499</id>
        <id>T1498.001</id>
        <id>T1498</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100078" level="1">
    <if_sid>100077</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)medium</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Flood detection alert with a medium severity level.</description>
    <group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1499,impact,T1498.001,T1498,flood,detect,dos,ddos,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: A flood detection alert with a medium severity level indicates that the system has detected an unusual surge in traffic that could potentially overwhelm network resources, but the immediate threat is assessed as moderate. This may suggest an early stage of a Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) attack or a misconfiguration that needs attention.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1499</id>
        <id>T1498.001</id>
        <id>T1498</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100079" level="1">
    <if_sid>100077</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)high</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Flood detection alert with a high severity level.</description>
    <group>high,one-on-one,s-a,T1499,impact,T1498.001,T1498,flood,detect,dos,ddos,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: A flood detection alert with a high severity level indicates that the network is experiencing a significant surge in traffic, likely pointing to an ongoing or imminent Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) attack. This level of severity suggests that the traffic volume is substantial enough to potentially disrupt services, degrade performance, or even cause outages.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1499</id>
        <id>T1498.001</id>
        <id>T1498</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100080" level="1">
    <if_sid>100077</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)critical</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Flood detection alert with a critical severity level.</description>
    <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,T1499,impact,T1498.001,T1498,flood,detect,dos,ddos,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: A flood detection alert with a critical severity level indicates that the network is under a severe and potentially devastating Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) attack. The traffic surge is so intense that it threatens to completely overwhelm network resources, causing widespread service outages, severe performance degradation, or total network failure.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1499</id>
        <id>T1498.001</id>
        <id>T1498</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100081" level="1" noalert="1">
    <if_sid>100050</if_sid>
    <action>block-url</action>
    <description>PaloAlto: The URL request was blocked because it matched a URL category configured to be blocked.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,T1566,initial-access,T1102,command-and-control,block,malicious,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The URL request was blocked because it matched a URL category that has been pre-configured for blocking, indicating that the attempted access was to a website or online resource categorized as unsafe or inappropriate according to the organization's security policies.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1566</id>
        <id>T1102</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100082" level="1">
    <if_sid>100081</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)medium</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: The URL request was blocked because it matched a URL category configured to be blocked with a medium severity level.</description>
    <group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1566,initial-access,T1102,command-and-control,block,malicious,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The URL request was blocked because it matched a URL category configured to be blocked with a medium severity level, indicating that the request was directed to a website or online resource deemed moderately risky by the organization's security policies. This might involve access to sites that could potentially expose users to security threats, such as spyware, adware, or sites with questionable content.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1566</id>
        <id>T1102</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100083" level="1">
    <if_sid>100081</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)high</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: The URL request was blocked because it matched a URL category configured to be blocked with a high severity level.</description>
    <group>high,one-on-one,s-a,T1566,initial-access,T1102,command-and-control,block,malicious,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The URL request was blocked because it matched a URL category configured to be blocked with a high severity level, indicating that the attempted access was to a highly risky or dangerous site. This could include URLs associated with known malware, phishing attacks, command-and-control servers, or other malicious content.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1566</id>
        <id>T1102</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100084" level="1">
    <if_sid>100081</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)critical</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: The URL request was blocked because it matched a URL category configured to be blocked with a critical severity level.</description>
    <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,T1566,initial-access,T1102,command-and-control,block,malicious,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The URL request was blocked because it matched a URL category configured to be blocked with a critical severity level, signifying an attempt to access a site that poses an extreme risk to security. This could involve URLs linked to severe threats such as ransomware, sophisticated phishing campaigns, or sites known for distributing malware.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1566</id>
        <id>T1102</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100085" level="1">
    <if_sid>100050</if_sid>
    <action>continue</action>
    <description>PaloAlto: A response to a block-continue URL page indicates that a block-continue request was permitted to proceed.</description>
   <group>medium,one-on-one,T1071,command-and-control,T1566,initial-access,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: A response to a block-continue URL page indicates that a user attempted to access a site that was initially blocked due to its URL category, but the security system allowed the request to proceed after the user acknowledged a warning or took action to continue. This highlights a potential area for user education on security policies.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1071</id>
        <id>T1566</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100086" level="1">
    <if_sid>100050</if_sid>
    <action>override-lockout</action>
    <description>PaloAlto: Too many failed admin override passcode attempts from the source IP. The IP is now blocked from accessing the block-override redirect page.</description>
   <group>medium,one-on-one,block,fail,T1110,credential-access,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The detection of too many failed admin override passcode attempts from a source IP, leading to the IP being blocked from accessing the block-override redirect page, indicates a potential security threat. This situation suggests that someone may be attempting to brute-force the override passcode to bypass security restrictions, which could compromise the integrity of the security system.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1110</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100091" level="1">
    <if_sid>100017</if_sid>
    <action>alert</action>
    <description>PaloAlto: Traffic containing matching data was detected but not blocked.</description>
   <group>medium,one-on-one,detect,T1071,command-and-control,T1048,exfiltration,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: When traffic containing matching data is detected but not blocked, it means that the security system identified traffic that corresponds to known threat patterns, sensitive data, or policy violations but did not take immediate action to stop it. This could be due to policy configurations that allow certain types of traffic through for monitoring purposes or because the detection threshold was met but not exceeded. While the traffic wasn’t blocked, this situation warrants careful attention.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1071</id>
        <id>T1048</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100092" level="1" noalert="1">
    <if_sid>100007</if_sid>
    <field name="log_subtype" type="pcre2">(?i)login</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: User logged in.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,login,T1078,defense-evasion,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: A user logged in, indicating a successful authentication event where the user credentials were verified, granting access to the system or network. This log entry is important for tracking user activity and monitoring for unauthorized access.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1078</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100093" level="1" noalert="1">
    <if_sid>100007</if_sid>
    <field name="log_subtype" type="pcre2">(?i)logout</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: User logged out.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,T1078,defense-evasion,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: A user logged out, marking the end of an active session where the user disconnected from the system or network. This log entry helps maintain a record of user sessions for security audits.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1078</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100094" level="1" noalert="1">
    <if_sid>100010,100012</if_sid>
    <field name="log_subtype" type="pcre2">(?i)crypto</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Encrypt and decrypt sensitive data within a configuration file to protect it from unauthorized access.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,T1573,command-and-control,T1027,defense-evasion,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: To encrypt and decrypt sensitive data within a configuration file, implement strong encryption algorithms, such as AES, to secure the data. Encryption ensures that even if the configuration file is accessed by unauthorized users, the sensitive data remains unreadable without the correct decryption key. Decryption is performed when the data needs to be used, ensuring that it is accessible only to authorized processes or users.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1573</id>
        <id>T1027</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100095" level="1">
    <if_sid>100094</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)low</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Encrypt and decrypt sensitive data within a configuration file to protect it from unauthorized access with a low severity level.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,T1573,command-and-control,T1027,defense-evasion,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: Encrypting and decrypting sensitive data within a configuration file with a low severity level indicates that while the data needs protection, the potential risk associated with unauthorized access is considered minimal. This could be for data that is not highly confidential but still requires some level of security.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1573</id>
        <id>T1027</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100096" level="1">
    <if_sid>100094</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)medium</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Encrypt and decrypt sensitive data within a configuration file to protect it from unauthorized access with a medium severity level.</description>
   <group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1573,command-and-control,T1027,defense-evasion,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: Encrypting and decrypting sensitive data within a configuration file with a medium severity level involves protecting information that, if exposed, could lead to moderate risks, such as unauthorized access to non-critical systems or internal operations. Enhanced security measures should be applied to prevent potential exploitation.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1573</id>
        <id>T1027</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100097" level="1">
    <if_sid>100094</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)high</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Encrypt and decrypt sensitive data within a configuration file to protect it from unauthorized access with a high severity level.</description>
   <group>high,one-on-one,s-a,T1573,command-and-control,T1027,defense-evasion,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: Encrypting and decrypting sensitive data within a configuration file with a high severity level is critical when the data is highly confidential or integral to the security of key systems. For such sensitive information, implement robust encryption standards, such as AES-256, and ensure the encryption keys are managed using a highly secure key management system (KMS) or hardware security module (HSM). Access to the decryption keys should be strictly limited to authorized personnel and processes, with multi-factor authentication (MFA) and stringent access controls in place.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1573</id>
        <id>T1027</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100098" level="1">
    <if_sid>100094</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)critical</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Encrypt and decrypt sensitive data within a configuration file to protect it from unauthorized access with a critical severity level.</description>
   <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,T1573,command-and-control,T1027,defense-evasion,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: Encrypting and decrypting sensitive data within a configuration file with a critical severity level is essential when the data holds highly sensitive or confidential information, such as encryption keys, credentials, or personally identifiable information (PII). In such cases, strong encryption standards like AES-256 must be applied, and access to the decryption keys must be tightly controlled using secure key management systems (KMS) or hardware security modules (HSM).
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1573</id>
        <id>T1027</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100101" level="1" noalert="1">
    <if_sid>100010,100012</if_sid>
    <field name="log_subtype" type="pcre2">(?i)dos</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Flood attack protection.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,T1498.001,T1498,impact,T1499.001,T1499,dos,attack,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: Flood Attack Protection. A critical severity detection signifies a full-scale flood attack aimed at crippling the network, potentially disrupting all services and causing major operational damage.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1498</id>
        <id>T1498.001</id>
        <id>T1499</id>
        <id>T1499.001</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100102" level="1">
    <if_sid>100101</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)low</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Flood attack protection with low severity.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,T1498.001,T1498,impact,T1499.001,T1499,dos,attack,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: Flood Attack Protection with low severity indicates that while the traffic levels are higher than usual, they do not pose an immediate threat. However, continued monitoring is advised to ensure that traffic patterns do not escalate to a more serious threat level.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1498</id>
        <id>T1498.001</id>
        <id>T1499</id>
        <id>T1499.001</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100103" level="1">
    <if_sid>100101</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)medium</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Denial-of-service (DoS) protection defends specific critical systems against flood attacks, especially devices that users access from the internet, such as web servers and database servers, and protects resources from session floods.</description>
   <group>medium,one-on-one,s-a,T1498.001,T1498,impact,T1499.001,T1499,dos,attack,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: Denial-of-service (DoS) protection with medium severity provides alerts when suspicious traffic patterns are detected, which could indicate an ongoing attack. The protection focuses on critical systems, ensuring that vital services remain available.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1498</id>
        <id>T1498.001</id>
        <id>T1499</id>
        <id>T1499.001</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100104" level="1">
    <if_sid>100101</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)high</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Denial-of-service (DoS) protection defends specific critical systems against flood attacks, especially devices that users access from the internet, such as web servers and database servers, and protects resources from session floods.</description>
   <group>high,one-on-one,s-a,T1498.001,T1498,impact,T1499.001,T1499,dos,attack,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: Denial-of-service (DoS) protection with high severity triggers alerts and implements mitigation strategies when potential attacks against critical systems are detected. Immediate actions may include blocking malicious IP addresses and rate-limiting connections.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1498</id>
        <id>T1498.001</id>
        <id>T1499</id>
        <id>T1499.001</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100105" level="1">
    <if_sid>100101</if_sid>
    <field name="severity" type="pcre2">(?i)critical</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Denial-of-service (DoS) protection defends specific critical systems against flood attacks, especially devices that users access from the internet, such as web servers and database servers, and protects resources from session floods.</description>
   <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,T1498.001,T1498,impact,T1499.001,T1499,dos,attack,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: Denial-of-service (DoS) protection with critical severity is vital for maintaining the integrity and availability of essential services. This level of protection employs advanced threat detection techniques and automated responses to mitigate severe attacks aimed at crippling critical infrastructure.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1498</id>
        <id>T1498.001</id>
        <id>T1499</id>
        <id>T1499.001</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100106" level="1">
    <if_sid>100010</if_sid>
    <field name="log_subtype" type="pcre2">(?i)pbf</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Detects policy-based forwarding overrides that direct traffic based on specific parameters like IP or traffic type.</description>
   <group>medium,one-on-one,T1572,command-and-control,policy,violation,T1484.001,T1484,defense-evasion,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: Policy-based forwarding (PBF) overrides are detected when traffic is deliberately routed based on specific parameters, such as source or destination IP addresses, traffic type, or applications, instead of default routing protocols. These overrides allow administrators to optimize network performance by redirecting certain traffic through predefined paths, which may bypass traditional routing mechanisms.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1572</id>
        <id>T1484</id>
        <id>T1484.001</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100108" level="1">
    <if_sid>100010,100012</if_sid>
    <field name="log_subtype" type="pcre2">(?i)routing</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Detects activity from routing daemons and dynamic routing protocols.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,T1071.001,T1071,T1016,command-and-control,discovery,T1572,T1040,credential-access,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: The routing daemon is a background process responsible for managing and distributing routing information across the network. It communicates with other routers and devices to dynamically update routing tables based on network changes. Dynamic routing refers to the automatic adjustment of routes in real-time, using routing protocols like OSPF, BGP, or RIP, to adapt to network conditions. Dynamic routing ensures optimal paths are selected for data packets, improving network efficiency, resilience, and reducing manual configuration. The routing daemon constantly monitors, updates, and propagates changes, ensuring that routes are always up-to-date based on current network topology.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1071.001</id>
        <id>T1016</id>
        <id>T1071</id>
        <id>T1572</id>
        <id>T1040</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100110" level="1">
    <if_sid>100010,100012</if_sid>
    <field name="log_subtype" type="pcre2">(?i)sslmgr</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Detects OCSP and CRL query requests from daemons and dataplane.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,T1071.001,T1071,command-and-control,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: Detection of OCSP (Online Certificate Status Protocol) and CRL (Certificate Revocation List) query requests from daemons and the data plane indicates that the network is actively checking the revocation status of SSL/TLS certificates. OCSP requests are used to obtain real-time information on the validity of a certificate, while CRL queries retrieve lists of revoked certificates. Monitoring these requests is essential for ensuring secure communications, as they help prevent the use of invalid or compromised certificates. If frequent or unusual query patterns are detected, it may indicate misconfigurations, potential attacks, or unauthorized attempts to bypass security measures. Immediate analysis and appropriate action should be taken to mitigate any identified risks.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1071</id>
        <id>T1071.001</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100111" level="1">
    <if_sid>100010,100012</if_sid>
    <field name="log_subtype" type="pcre2">(?i)sslvpn</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Monitors secure web pages accessed via SSL VPN and GlobalProtect.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,T1133,persistence,T1071.001,T1071,command-and-control,vpn,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: Secure web pages for SSL VPN and GlobalProtect provide encrypted connections for remote users accessing corporate networks. SSL VPN offers user-friendly interfaces for login and resource access, incorporating features like multi-factor authentication and role-based access. GlobalProtect enhances security by performing endpoint compliance checks before access, ensuring only authorized devices connect. Both solutions prioritize encryption and user authentication to protect against threats and ensure a secure remote access experience.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1133</id>
        <id>T1071.001</id>
        <id>T1071</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100113" level="1">
    <if_sid>100010,100012</if_sid>
    <field name="log_subtype" type="pcre2">(?i)url-filtering</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Monitors URL filtering activity to block or allow access based on defined security policies.</description>
   <group>low,one-on-one,T1204.001,T1204,execution,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: Monitoring URL filtering activity is essential for controlling web access based on predefined security policies. This process involves analyzing user requests to access specific websites and determining whether to allow or block those requests based on the organization's security criteria. Effective URL filtering helps protect against malicious sites, reduces exposure to harmful content, and ensures compliance with company policies.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1204.001</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>


<!-- Contextual Correlation Rule -->




<rule id="100114" level="1">
    <if_sid>100017</if_sid>
    <field name="assets" type="pcre2">^(?i)Critical$</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Data filtering detection on critical assets</description>
    <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,contextual-correlation,T1071,command-and-control,T1040,policy,violation,credential-access,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: This rule identifies instances where a data pattern matched a Data Filtering profile, specifically targeting critical assets. Such events may indicate unauthorized data transfer attempts, potential data exfiltration, or violations of data handling policies.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1071</id>
        <id>T1040</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100115" level="1">
    <if_sid>100027</if_sid>
    <field name="assets" type="pcre2">^(?i)Critical$</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Flood detected through a zone protection profile on critical asset</description>
   <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,contextual-correlation,detect,flood,T1499,impact,T1498,dos,ddos,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: This rule detects flood attacks, such as SYN floods or UDP floods, identified by a Zone Protection profile targeting critical assets. These attacks may indicate an attempt to overwhelm the network infrastructure or disrupt critical services. 
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1499</id>
        <id>T1498</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100116" level="1">
    <if_sid>100032</if_sid>
    <field name="assets" type="pcre2">^(?i)Critical$</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Packet-based attack protection activated by a zone protection profile on critical asset</description>
   <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,contextual-correlation,attack,T1040,credential-access,T1071.001,T1071,command-and-control,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: This rule identifies instances where packet-based attack protection mechanisms were activated by a Zone Protection profile to safeguard critical assets. Such activations may indicate attempts to exploit vulnerabilities through crafted packets or denial-of-service attacks.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1040</id>
        <id>T1071</id>
        <id>T1071.001</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100117" level="1">
    <if_sid>100041</if_sid>
    <field name="assets" type="pcre2">^(?i)Critical$</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Scan detected via a zone protection profile on critical asset</description>
   <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,contextual-correlation,detect,recon,T1595,reconnaissance,T1046,discovery,T1595.002,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: This rule identifies scanning activity detected through a Zone Protection profile targeting critical assets. Scans are often precursors to attacks, as adversaries attempt to gather information about open ports, services, or vulnerabilities on critical systems. 
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1595</id>
        <id>T1046</id>
        <id>T1595.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100118" level="1">
    <if_sid>100046</if_sid>
    <field name="assets" type="pcre2">^(?i)Critical$</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Spyware detected via an anti-spyware profile on critical asset</description>
   <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,contextual-correlation,detect,malware,T1587.001,T1587,resource-development,T1204,execution,T1588,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: This rule detects spyware activity identified through an Anti-Spyware profile targeting critical assets. Spyware can compromise sensitive data, monitor system activities, or serve as a foothold for further malicious actions.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1587</id>
        <id>T1587.001</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1588</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100119" level="1">
    <if_sid>100050</if_sid>
    <field name="assets" type="pcre2">^(?i)Critical$</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: URL filtering activity recorded on critical asset</description>
   <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,contextual-correlation,policy,violation,T1204.001,T1204,execution,T1071,command-and-control,T1566,initial-access,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: This rule logs URL filtering activity recorded on critical assets, indicating attempts to access or interact with web resources that may violate security policies. Such activities could involve access to restricted or malicious sites, potentially exposing critical systems to threats. 
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1566</id>
        <id>T1204.001</id>
        <id>T1071</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100120" level="1">
    <if_sid>100055</if_sid>
    <field name="assets" type="pcre2">^(?i)Critical$</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Virus detected through an antivirus profile on critical asset</description>
   <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,contextual-correlation,T1587.001,T1587,T1204.002,T1204,execution,resource-development,malicious,detect,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: This rule identifies virus activity detected by an Antivirus profile targeting critical assets. Such activity may indicate malware infection attempts or the presence of malicious files on the system.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1587</id>
        <id>T1587.001</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1204.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100121" level="1">
    <if_sid>100060</if_sid>
    <field name="assets" type="pcre2">^(?i)Critical$</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Vulnerability exploit detected through a vulnerability protection profile on critical asset</description>
   <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,contextual-correlation,vulnerability,detect,T1068,privilege-escalation,T1190,initial-access,T1588.006,resource-development,T1588,T1404,T1587,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: This rule detects attempts to exploit vulnerabilities in critical assets, identified by a Vulnerability Protection profile. Such exploits may target software, operating systems, or applications with known weaknesses, aiming to gain unauthorized access, escalate privileges, or disrupt operations. 
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1587</id>
        <id>T1404</id>
        <id>T1588</id>
        <id>T1190</id>
        <id>T1068</id>
        <id>T1588.006</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100122" level="1">
    <if_sid>100064</if_sid>
    <field name="assets" type="pcre2">^(?i)Critical$</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Wildfire verdict generated for file analysis on critical asset</description>
   <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,contextual-correlation,sandbox,T1497,defense-evasion,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: This rule captures instances where a WildFire Verdict is generated after a firewall sends a file associated with a critical asset to a cloud-based malware analysis service. The verdict determines if the file is malicious, which may indicate an attempt to introduce malware into the environment.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1497</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100123" level="1">
    <if_sid>100068</if_sid>
    <field name="assets" type="pcre2">^(?i)Critical$</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Wildfire-virus detected through an antivirus profile on critical asset</description>
    <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,contextual-correlation,T1587.001,T1587,T1204.002,T1204,execution,resource-development,malicious,detect,sandbox,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: When a virus detected through an Antivirus profile is categorized as a "WildFire-virus," it means that the malware has been identified as a threat that has been analyzed and classified by a cloud-based malware analysis service, such as Palo Alto Networks' WildFire. This classification indicates that the virus has been recognized as a known malicious entity with potentially severe impacts.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1587</id>
        <id>T1587.001</id>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1204.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100124" level="1">
    <if_sid>100073</if_sid>
    <field name="assets" type="pcre2">^(?i)Critical$</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Threat or url detected but not blocked on critical asset</description>
   <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,contextual-correlation,detect,T1204.001,T1204,execution,T1562.006,T1562,defense-evasion,T1566.002,T1566,initial-access,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: This rule identifies instances where a threat or URL was detected by security profiles monitoring critical assets but was not blocked. Such activity may indicate an attempt to access potentially malicious or restricted resources without immediate enforcement action.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1204</id>
        <id>T1562.006</id>
        <id>T1204.001</id>
        <id>T1562</id>
        <id>T1566</id>
        <id>T1566.002</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100125" level="1">
    <if_sid>100077</if_sid>
    <field name="assets" type="pcre2">^(?i)Critical$</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Flood detection alert on critical asset</description>
   <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,contextual-correlation,T1499,impact,T1498.001,T1498,flood,detect,dos,ddos,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: This rule generates an alert when flood detection mechanisms identify potential flood attacks targeting critical assets. Such attacks, including SYN floods or UDP floods, aim to overwhelm network resources and disrupt services. 
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1499</id>
        <id>T1498.001</id>
        <id>T1498</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>

<rule id="100126" level="1">
    <if_sid>100085</if_sid>
    <field name="assets" type="pcre2">^(?i)Critical$</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Block-continue url request permitted on critical asset</description>
   <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,contextual-correlation,T1071,command-and-control,T1566,initial-access,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: This rule identifies instances where a response to a block-continue URL page indicates that access to a previously blocked URL was permitted to proceed for a critical asset. Such actions may represent authorized exceptions or potential security policy bypasses. 
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1071</id>
        <id>T1566</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100127" level="1">
    <if_sid>100086</if_sid>
    <field name="assets" type="pcre2">^(?i)Critical$</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Source ip blocked after excessive failed admin override passcode attempts on critical asset</description>
   <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,contextual-correlation,block,fail,T1110,credential-access,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: This rule identifies and blocks a source IP after too many failed attempts to input an admin override passcode when accessing the block-override redirect page for a critical asset. Such activity may indicate unauthorized access attempts or brute-force behavior targeting administrative controls.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1110</id>
    </mitre>
</rule> 

<rule id="100128" level="1">
    <if_sid>100091</if_sid>
    <field name="assets" type="pcre2">^(?i)Critical$</field>
    <description>PaloAlto: Traffic with matching data detected but not blocked on critical asset</description>
   <group>critical,one-on-one,s-a,contextual-correlation,detect,T1071,command-and-control,T1048,exfiltration,</group>
   <info type="text">
    Description: This rule identifies network traffic containing data that matches predefined security profiles, targeting critical assets. Although the traffic was detected, it was not actively blocked, which could indicate an exception, a misconfiguration, or a potential oversight in the security policy.
    </info>
    <mitre>
        <id>T1071</id>
        <id>T1048</id>
    </mitre>
</rule>



</group>